Academia Sinica's February Governor's Salary Banquet Lecture Begins
中央研究院の2月知事給与晩餐会講演会が始まります
We ask Vice President Huang Bansheng to host for us
黄伴生副大統領に司会をお願いします
thank you all distinguished guests good night everyone
ゲストの皆様、ありがとうございます、皆さんおやすみなさい
Good night
おやすみ
Today was supposed to be hosted by Vice President Chen Jianren
今日は陳建仁副総統が主催する予定だった
But because he's going abroad, I'm the agent
でも彼は海外に行くので私が代理人です
Then next week it seems to be me too
じゃあ来週は私もそうなるみたいです
Next week's Humanities
来週の人文科学
so i'm going to read the speech
だからスピーチを読んでみるよ
Because I'm the Associate Dean for Humanities
私は人文科学の副学部長だから
so relatively unfamiliar
比較的馴染みのない
Feel sorry
気の毒だと思う
Welcome to today's feast of knowledge
今日の知識の饗宴へようこそ
Everyone knows that the Feast of Knowledge is
知識の饗宴は、誰もが知っています。
Academia Sinica is a very important activity to promote popular science education
中央研究院は大衆科学教育を促進する非常に重要な活動です
have been around for a long time
行之有年
Every month we invite experts and scholars from various fields inside and outside the school
毎月、学内外のさまざまな分野の専門家や学者を招聘しています。
Come here to talk about the latest academic research and scientific development
最新の学術研究や科学の発展について話し合うためにここに来てください
It is our pleasure to invite you to our hospital to divide and administer biology tonight
今夜、生物学を分割して管理するために私たちの病院にあなたを招待できることを嬉しく思います
Research Fellow
研究員
Ms. Bien
儀師美燕氏
Let's talk about world food security and crisis
世界の食糧安全保障と危機について話しましょう
where to go
どこへ行く
Well, everyone saw that the self-introduction of the academician mentioned
さて、アカデミアンに記載されている自己紹介をご覧ください
Because he saw his inner and outer grandfathers as eggs since he was a child
なぜなら、彼は子供の頃から内なる祖父と外の祖父を卵として見ていたからです。
See this farmer and nature Hakata
この農家と博多の自然を見る
So he chose his
そこで彼は自分のものを選びました
subject of this study
この研究の主題
is rice
米です
Then he started from the university and research institute
その後大学や研究機関からスタート
I studied at the Department of Occupational Diseases of Central University
私は中央大学職業病学科で学びました
Department of Occupational Pathology
職業病理学部門
Then go to the United States to apply for a license
その後、アメリカに行ってライセンスを申請します
After receiving a Ph.D. in pathology from the University of Arkansas
アーカンソー大学で病理学の博士号を取得後
Postdoctoral research in the United States
米国でのポスドク研究
The hospital came back to our hospital in 1989
1989年に当院に戻ってきました。
Institute of Molecular Biology Continuing Research
分子生物学研究所 継続研究
Choose the most local
最もローカルなものを選択してください
and is the most important food crop in the world
そして世界で最も重要な食用作物です
Rice as research material
研究材料としての米
So far, many breakthrough studies have found that
これまでに多くの画期的な研究で次のようなことがわかっています。
For example, the discovery of a gene that controls flood tolerance in rice
例えば、イネの洪水耐性を制御する遺伝子の発見
Level Molecular Mechanism
分子機構
Unraveling only rice seeds among all stocks for decades
数十年かけて全株の中から種籾だけを解き明かす
The secret to germination and growth in water
水中での発芽と成長の秘密
The results were published in important international journals
結果は重要な国際雑誌に掲載されました
Hospital doctors are also invited to speak at international conferences
病院の医師も国際会議での講演に招待される
Speech to domestic and foreign organizations
国内外の団体での講演
And won many domestic and foreign awards
国内外で数々の賞を受賞
Elected as a Fellow of the Academy of Sciences for the Developing World in 2005
2005 年に発展途上世界科学アカデミーのフェローに選出
Elected to the American Association for the Advancement of Science in 2005
2005 年に米国科学振興協会の会員に選出
In 2012, that is, last year, he was elected as an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences
2012年、つまり昨年、彼は中国科学院の会員に選出された
Since 1993, the academician successfully completed the world's first rice gene transfer using agrobacterium
1993年以来、学者はアグロバクテリウムを使用した世界初のイネの遺伝子導入に成功しました。
He continues to use genetic engineering technology to improve rice varieties
彼は遺伝子組み換え技術を使って米の品種改良を続けている
Developed many innovative biotechnologies
数々の革新的なバイオテクノロジーを開発
He also led the teams of Chung Hsing University and Asia University in the Institute of Agriculture, Academia Sinica
彼はまた、中央研究院農業研究所の中興大学と亜細亜大学のチームを率いました。
From 2003 to 2012, a huge rice map was completed
2003年から2012年にかけて巨大な米マップが完成
Mutant stock and gene database
変異株および遺伝子データベース
Discovered the functions of many important genes
多くの重要な遺伝子の機能を発見
Recently, BioGate, a foundation funded by BioGate, has received funding
最近、BioGate が資金提供する財団である BioGate が資金提供を受けました。
Study how to increase rice photosynthesis efficiency to yield
イネの光合成効率を高めて収量を高める研究
Significantly enhance the international life of rice research in Taiwan
台湾におけるイネ研究の国際的活動を大幅に強化
Then in another introduction
それではまた別の紹介で
He also mentioned that the population has been increasing because
彼はまた、人口が増加している理由についても述べました。
However, there is obviously no significant increase in food
ただし、粒子は明らかに大きく増加しませんでした
Such a game is actually a very
このようなゲームは実際には非常に
a challenging question
挑戦的な質問
last year
去年
ah
ああ
group just
グループだけ
The Secretary-General of the Chinese Academy of Sciences came to the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
中国科学院事務総長が中医薬院を訪問
because that day
あの日だから
When all the officers don't know where to go
警官全員がどこに行けばいいのかわからないとき
I had to meet him
彼に会わなければならなかった
he raised a question
彼は質問をした
he just said
彼はちょうど言った
Pope is against genetic modification
ローマ法王は遺伝子組み換えに反対
this
これ
ah
ああ
rice
米
he obviously
彼は明らかに
Is my report right?
私の報告は正しいでしょうか？
if i am wrong i will
私が間違っていたらそうします
I'll be better anyway
とにかく良くなるよ
this love
この愛
He said but the pope is the pope who just abdicated
彼は言ったが、法王は退位したばかりの法王だ
against genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えに反対する
He said that because the Pope in his youth
彼がそう言ったのは、若い頃の教皇が
study in germany
ドイツに留学する
Influenced by Heidegger's philosophy
ハイデッガー哲学の影響
Then Heidegger is of course the second century
そうなるとハイデッガーはもちろん2世紀です
very important philosophy
非常に重要な哲学
one of the most important philosophers
最も重要な哲学者の一人
He opposes excessive intervention and destruction
彼は過度の介入と破壊に反対します
but he said
しかし彼は言いました
He thinks he sees things differently than the Pope
彼はローマ法王とは物事の見方が違うと考えている
pope your people your believers
教皇、あなたの民、あなたの信者たち
What a sorrow
なんという悲しみ
How can you not modify his genes
彼の遺伝子を改変しないわけがない
have more of this
これをもっと持っています
So I guess I'm hosting today's talk
それで今日の講演は私が司会をすることになると思います
Reminds me of this conversation last year
去年のこの会話を思い出します
Then I think today's topic is very meaningful
それなら今日の話題はとても意味があると思います
It is world food security and crisis
それは世界の食糧安全保障と危機です
not where to go but where to go
どこに行くかではなく、どこに行くか
we applaud
私たちは拍手を送ります
Yu Xiuyan
ユウ・シウヤン
good
良い
Vice President Wang thank you for the introduction
王副社長、ご紹介ありがとうございます
and good night everyone
そして皆さんおやすみ
Good night
おやすみ
Thank you so much for a hard day
大変な一日を本当にありがとうございました
Then I have to come here for class in the evening
それから、夕方には授業のためにここに来なければなりません
I wish to say this is not a serious class
これは深刻なクラスではないと言いたいのですが、
because what we are going to talk about today
なぜなら、私たちが今日話そうとしていることは
Is it related to our current life and future life
それは私たちの現在の生活と将来の生活に関係していますか
are closely related
密接に関係している
is a very important topic
非常に重要なトピックです
we should all know
私たちは皆知っておくべきです
I hope that you will finally feel that
最終的にはそう感じてもらえると思います
don't need this trip
この旅行は必要ありません
I'll wait
待ちます
This is because I watched this speech
このスピーチを見たからです
Queued for two hours is a bit long
2時間並ぶのはちょっと長い
Then I hope that it can be done within an hour and a half
それでは1時間半以内に出来ればと思います
end it within
以内に終わらせる
and leave some time for people to ask this question
人々がこの質問をするための時間を残しておきます
because it's a matter of great concern
それは非常に懸念される問題だから
I often go out to lecture in class
私は授業の講義によく出かけます
really everyone cares
本当にみんな気にかけてる
Then I feel that there are many places I don’t understand
そうすると、理解できないところがたくさんある気がします
Then we need to make some clarifications
それから、いくつか説明する必要があります
The media is also very concerned about this issue.
メディアもこの問題を非常に懸念しています。
You can always watch
いつでも見ることができます
The media often come to visit me
メディアがよく私を訪ねてきます
discuss these issues
これらの問題について話し合う
So I think the media, the people
だからメディアも国民もそうだと思う
In fact, they are very concerned about this issue
実際、彼らはこの問題を非常に懸念しています
I feel like it's just the government that doesn't really care
政府だけが無関心な気がする
So I hope there is still a chance
だからまだチャンスがあることを願っています
enable them to understand the seriousness of the problem
彼らが問題の深刻さを理解できるようにする
So let's start now with what I'm going to talk about
それでは、これからお話しする内容から始めましょう
So in this twentieth century
それでこの20世紀には
In the past 100 years, our technology has advanced very fast
過去 100 年間、私たちのテクノロジーは急速に進歩しました
From burning this without a light to being able to use a computer now
光を使わずにこれを燃やしてから、コンピューターを使用できるようになりました
Do various searches with Google
Googleでいろいろ検索してみよう
Then from this ship to space, it is said that it can fly to the sky
そしてこの船から宇宙へ、空まで飛べるそうです
technology advances very fast
テクノロジーは非常に速く進歩します
But at the same time, in this one hundred years
しかし同時に、この百年の間に
Our population has also nearly quadrupled
人口もほぼ4倍になりました
The rate of increase of this population
この人口の増加率
This one was written from 1750
これは 1750 年に書かれたものです
you see 1500 years
1500年が見えます
15 about 607 years later
約607年後の15
From the beginning, the speed of increase is very fast
最初から伸びるスピードがとても早い
wait a minute we'll mention there was a green revolution
ちょっと待ってください、緑の革命があったと言います
was started in 1960
1960年に開始されました
until almost the end of 2000
2000年の終わり近くまで
around this time
この頃
during the first green revolution
第一次緑の革命のとき
The population is growing at its fastest rate
人口は最速のペースで増加している
Now our population increase is not over
人口増加はまだ終わっていない
did not stop
止まらなかった
actual birth rate
実際の出生率
It's actually going down
実際は下がってるよ
But because of these populations
しかし、これらの人口のせいで
In the next 30, 40 years
今後30年、40年で
he will start
彼は始めるだろう
No 20, 30 years
いいえ、20年、30年
will begin to have many children
多くの子供を産み始めるだろう
so this is a
これは
It will continue to be the cause of our population pressure
それは今後も人口圧力の原因となるだろう
the distribution of the population
人口の分布
From Africa Latin America Asia Oceania
アフリカ出身 ラテンアメリカ アジア オセアニア
North America Europe or Worldwide
北米 ヨーロッパまたは世界各地
You can see that Africa is indeed the most populous
確かにアフリカが最も人口が多いことがわかります
latin america asia
ラテンアメリカ アジア
But what about the rate of population increase?
しかし、人口増加率はどうでしょうか？
this different color
この違う色
are saying
言っています
it's at a different time
それは違う時間です
Indeed, it has been decreasing
減少してきています
so far
ここのところ
rate of population increase
人口増加率
In fact, there is no rate of death
実際、死亡率より速いものはない
how high is it
どのくらいの高さですか
One is 2.5% One is 2.2%
1 つは 2.5% 1 つは 2.2%
so we all know
だから私たちは皆知っています
population cannot increase
人口は増えない
can't be that fast
そんなに速くはできない
But the problem is that so many people exist
しかし問題は、人が多すぎるということです
it is going to have a baby
それは赤ちゃんを産む予定です
Then how do we feed so many people
では、どうやってこれほど多くの人に食事を与えることができるのでしょうか
At the same time, a very important issue related to food is energy.
同時に、食に関わる非常に重要な問題はエネルギーです。
The proportion of this energy
このエネルギーの割合は
Oil 37%
石油三七%
Coal 25%
石炭 25%
Then Natural Gas 23%
次に天然ガス 23%
Other very small proportions are some other energy sources
他の非常に小さな割合は他のエネルギー源です
What about nuclear power?
原子力についてはどうですか？
Press 6% again
もう一度6%を押す
That's biomass
それがバイオマスです
reproductive energy
生殖エネルギー
And then hydrogen or solar wind and so on
あとは水素とか太陽風とか。
Its proportion is actually very low
その割合は実際には非常に低いです
Of course, what else is hot?
もちろん、他に何が熱いですか？
there are others this and others
他にもこれや他のものがあります
it's sun hot
太陽が暑いです
that's solar and so on
それは太陽光発電などです
So our share of renewable energy
つまり、再生可能エネルギーのシェアは
So far there is no way to improve
今のところ改善する方法はありません
because it costs too much
費用がかかりすぎるので
The current energy
現在のエネルギー
relatively low price
比較的低価格
So everyone is interested in the development of this renewable energy
誰もがこの再生可能エネルギーの開発に興味を持っています
not so positive
あまりポジティブではない
That's just a few days ago
それはほんの数日前のことです
What about our gasoline?
私たちのガソリンはどうですか？
This gas once in Taiwan
このガスはかつて台湾にありました
rose to an all-time high
史上最高値に上昇した
Although it has dropped a little these days
最近は少し減りましたが
But I believe this number will still be a normal
でもこの数字はまだ普通だと思う
In this way, the energy is actually reduced.
このようにして、エネルギーは実際に減少します。
Many of the things we mentioned just now
今お話ししたことの多くは
various energy sources that currently exist
現在存在するさまざまなエネルギー源
Able to use in addition to coal
石炭以外にも使用可能
It can be used for more than two hundred years
二百年以上使える
Most of the others are around fifty years old
他の人はほとんどが50歳くらいです
gasoline or natural gas
ガソリンまたは天然ガス
natural gas course most recent usa
天然ガスコース 最新の米国
it has found some
それはいくつかを見つけました
oily natural gas
油性天然ガス
so yes things are changing a bit
そう、状況は少し変わってきています
There are other sources of energy like remineralization
再石灰化などの他のエネルギー源もあります
about fifty years
約50年
So everyone is speculating on nuclear energy
だからみんな原子力エネルギーについて憶測してる
Because it's useless in the future
将来的には役に立たないから
So the energy goes down like this
こうやってエネルギーが下がっていくんですね
This is how the population rises
こうやって人口は増えるんだな
But the speed at which our food is produced
しかし、私たちの食べ物が生産されるスピードは
actually slow down
実際に速度を落とす
Such a gap between population and food
人口と食糧の間にはこれほどのギャップがある
Let's see now that this is 2010
これが 2010 年であることを見てみましょう
We are still at the beginning
私たちはまだ始まりにいます
Nearly 40 years to come
これから約 40 年
such a long time
とても長い間
How do we fill this big gap
この大きなギャップをどうやって埋めるか
it's a big challenge
それは大きな挑戦だ
so many people
たくさんの人々
every mouth
すべての口
Every mouth has something to eat
どの口にも何か食べるものがある
How can we produce enough of this food
どうすればこの食料を十分に生産できるでしょうか
to feed so many people
たくさんの人に食事を与えるために
This is where we study plants
ここは植物を研究する場所です
research in agriculture
農業の研究
study of rice
お米の勉強
We often think about this question
私たちはよくこの質問について考えます
But I think people who do medicine
でも、医療をやっている人たちは、
probably don't think about it
おそらくそれについては考えていない
people in medicine want to say
医学関係者が言いたいのは
people are still healthy
人々はまだ健康です
grow thinner
痩せる
But I was at the United Daily News 10 years ago
でも私は10年前ユナイテッド・デイリー・ニュースにいた
I wrote an article at that time
その時に記事を書きました
It is said that a healthy and long-lived human being may not have enough to eat in a decade or two
健康で長生きした人間でも、10年か20年で十分な食べ物がなくなる可能性があると言われています。
So it's been 10 years
それで10年経ちました
I was talking about ten or twenty years
10年か20年くらいの話をしてた
But now it's been 10 years
でも、もう10年も経ったのですね
In fact, the problem is getting worse
実際、問題はさらに悪化している
That doesn't seem to have attracted too much attention.
それはあまり注目を集めていないようです。
let's start now
今すぐ始めましょう
Let me tell you first
最初に言っておきます
Where is the serious form of the problem to be addressed today
今日対処すべき問題の深刻な形態はどこにあるのか
But first let me give you some background
まず最初に背景を説明させてください
That is, how does our food come from?
つまり、私たちの食べ物はどのようにして作られるのでしょうか？
Then our human culture actually followed agriculture
そして私たちの人類の文化は実際に農業に続いたものでした
3.8 billion years ago
38億年前
Life begins on our planet
生命は私たちの地球上で始まります
and then successively
そして続いて
Then some various creatures came out.
すると、いろいろな生き物が出てきました。
what about this flower
この花はどうですか
Where's the first flower and insect?
最初の花と虫はどこですか？
Appeared about 130,000,000 years ago
約1億3千万年前に出現
Homo sapiens really have such a developed mind
ホモ・サピエンスは本当に発達した知性を持っている
What about this award?
この賞はどうでしょうか？
appeared between 400,000 and 250,000 years ago
40万年から25万年前に出現した
So in the history of this earth
この地球の歴史の中で
came very late
とても遅く来た
But it is the smartest animal
しかし、それは最も賢い動物です
but also the most destructive animal
しかし、最も破壊的な動物でもあります
what about our ancestors
私たちの先祖はどうですか
when it first started
最初に始まったとき
he hunts
彼は狩りをする
He runs wherever there are animals
彼は動物がいればどこでも走ります
That's why it migrates everywhere
だからどこにでも移動するんだよ
So from Africa 130,000 years ago
13万年前のアフリカから
Start migrating to Europe
ヨーロッパへの移住を始める
Then this Asia
それからこのアジア
Then to America
それからアメリカへ
such a migration
そのような移住
That's what our ancestors said
それは私たちの先祖が言ったことです
Wow, it's really tiring to fight all over the place.
うーん、あちこちで戦うのは本当に疲れます。
But no one owns a grocery store
しかし、食料品店を所有する人は誰もいません
how do we settle down
どうやって落ち着くのか
Do we still want to keep pulling like this?
まだこのまま引っ張り続けたいですか？
so what
だから何
They found out one day that there seemed to be some food somewhere
ある日、彼らはどこかに食べ物があるらしいことに気づきました
can we stop there
そこで止めてもいいですか
can be used as food
食品として使用できます
So in the beginning, they won't keep walking
だから最初は歩き続けられない
At the beginning, it was a little bit closer to the area of ​​grain production.
最初は穀物の産地にもう少し近かったんです。
start walking around there
そこら辺を歩き始める
And in the end, I found this grain
そして結局、この食べ物は見つかりましたか？
We can also plant it to reproduce it
成長させて再現することもできます
So when more and more food is planted
それで、より多くの食物が植えられると、
it settles down
それは落ち着く
So the ancestors settled down
それで祖先は定住した
So now there are still many chairs in the world
世界にはまだ椅子がたくさんある
That is, we can see that this was developed by human beings.
つまり、人間が開発したものであることが分かります。
Gikyo
宜京
In addition to planting this
これを植えるほかに、
Of course humans are just speaking from Africa
もちろん人間はアフリカから話しているだけです
means from africa
アフリカからという意味
to various countries
いろいろな国へ
After that, everyone started to grow this crop
その後、みんながこの作物を作り始めました
He also started to improve
彼も改善し始めた
Then many places are doing this at the same time
それから多くの場所がこれを同時に行っています
So 10,000 years ago
つまり1万年前
In this America they have corn
このアメリカにはトウモロコシがある
pumpkins, beans, etc.
かぼちゃとか豆とかそういうもの
Thirteen thousand years ago in Europe there were
1万3千年前のヨーロッパには、
wheat barley beans
小麦大麦豆
that big
那大
What about China nine thousand years ago
9000年前の中国はどうだったのか
started with soybeans and so on
大豆などから始まった
So what about this culture?
実はこの文化は
is in many places
多くの場所にあります
while developing
開発中
Then our ancestors were very powerful
それから私たちの祖先は非常に強力でした
from them to us
彼らから私たちへ
this latest this
この最新のこれ
Where's the breeder?
ブリーダーはどこですか？
Breeding techniques that can be exploited
活用できる繁殖技術
This crop can be improved
この作物は改良できる
So for thousands of years
だから何千年もの間
Humans have used breeding
人類は繁殖を利用してきた
to engineer the genes of countless crops
無数の作物の遺伝子を操作する
this is raw corn
これは生のトウモロコシです
it encourages very little
それはほとんど励みになりません
the shell is very hard
殻はとても硬いです
you can hardly bite
ほとんど噛めません
that's the corn now
それは今のトウモロコシです
This is the old rice
これが古米です
As soon as the bones grow up, they fall down
骨は成長するとすぐに落ちてしまいます
just fall
ただ落ちるだけ
fell into the water
水に落ちた
That's the current rice
それが今のお米です
that's wheat
それは小麦です
this is tomato
これはトマトです
This former tomato is now a tomato
かつてのトマトは今ではトマトになっている
In the past, it was like a sunflower, like a small wild flower
昔はひまわりのような、小さな野の花のようなものだった
Now it can be as big as a pot
今では鍋ほどの大きさになることもあります
So our jade seed scientists are very powerful
したがって、私たちの翡翠種子の科学者は非常に強力です
These different crops can be
これらのさまざまな作物は、
make it into the present we can see
私たちが見ることができる現在にそれを作ります
Such delicious food
こんなにおいしい食べ物
So this is actually other than plants
実はこれは植物以外のものなんです
Where is our main line?
私たちの本線はどこですか？
Also started to make this jade seed of many different plants
また、さまざまな植物からこの翡翠の種を作り始めました
This includes a lot of domestic animals
これには多くの家畜が含まれます
Jiaqin
嘉琴
Then you see this home piano is very powerful
そうすれば、この秦は非常に強力であることがわかります
the bird
鳥
There are many kinds of chicken
鶏肉もたくさんの種類があります
Pre-order a variety of different varieties like this
こんな感じで色々な種類をご予約いただけます
what about the animals
動物はどうですか
pig grows bigger
豚は大きくなる
From wild boar to domestic pig
イノシシから家畜豚へ
cow
牛
from bison great
バイソングレートより
become a smaller cow
小さな牛になる
etc. various
などなどいろいろ
that's great
それは素晴らしいことです
Watching dogs can make such a big difference
犬を見ることは大きな違いを生む
big to small
大きいものから小さいものまで
It's all about taro seeds
それはすべてタロイモの種についてです
What about taro seeds?
タロイモの種はどうでしょうか？
In fact, genes are constantly changing.
実際、遺伝子は常に変化しています。
Genetics are constantly mutating
遺伝子は常に変異している
At the same time, humans are also transforming their own experience.
同時に、人類は自らの経験も変革しつつあります。
We went from having to climb a tree to pick
木に登って採る必要がなくなりました
banana start
バナナスタート
like a monkey
猿のように
Then slowly we can stand up
それからゆっくりと立ち上がることができます
can tear or something
破れたりする可能性があります
can work
働ける
But because now Google
しかし、今ではGoogleだから
Our people are starting to recover again
私たちの人々は再び回復し始めています
with our ancestors
私たちの先祖たちと一緒に
almost
ほとんど
lie down again
また横になる
often mostly
たいていの場合
I often lie on this table again
私はまたこのテーブルによく横になります
so what about humans
では人間はどうでしょうか
also modifying our own genes
私たち自身の遺伝子も改変する
Are you going to get married and have kids?
結婚して子供を産むつもりですか？
Generations are different
世代が違うんだよ
OK
OK
ok then again
わかりました、それではもう一度
let's talk again
また話しましょう
Our Traditional Breeding Techniques
伝統的な飼育技術
Why can we seal the doctor's food
なぜドクターズフードを封印できるのでしょうか？
Breeding?
育種？
What about the crops of the natural world?
自然界の作物はどうでしょうか？
it is likely to have a lot of variation
かなりバリエーションがありそうです
like childbearing as an example
例として出産など
it has
それは持っています
The bone ear is very big
骨耳はとても大きいです
some are very small
いくつかは非常に小さいです
so our ancestors were smart
だから私たちの祖先は賢かった
then start putting
それから置き始めます
What about the relatively large seed of encouragement?
比較的大きな励ましの種についてはどうでしょうか。
start to breed
繁殖を始める
because in fact it's
なぜなら実際それは
What about this Yumi package?
このユミのパッケージはどうですか？
big and small
大小
It has something to do with its genetic inheritance
それは遺伝と関係がある
So after many generations
それで何世代も経ってから
Such breeding should be selected
このような品種を選択する必要があります
now we can see
今、私たちは見ることができます
Such an excellent rice variety
こんなに素晴らしいお米の品種
What about this evidence?
この証拠はどうでしょうか？
is in mohigan
モヒガンにいる
Because rice farming started from this side of Central America
米作りは中米のこちら側から始まったものだから
Nakanami
中南美
Yumi
ユミ
mohiganfa
モヒガンファ
Maize was discovered 7,000 years ago
トウモロコシは7,000年前に発見されました
The fossils they dug up were so small
彼らが掘り出した化石はとても小さかった
Then it was discovered that the dug out was getting bigger and bigger
すると、その穴がどんどん大きくなっていることが分かりました。
That is, as recently as five hundred years ago,
つまり、500年ほど前に、
Already fossils have gotten so big
すでに化石はこんなに大きくなっている
so this is a proof
これが証拠です
It's the corn seed
それはトウモロコシの種です
Let the size of this bone marrow continue to increase
この骨髄のサイズが増加し続けるようにします
So the jade seed of corn actually comes from
つまり、トウモロコシのヒスイの種は実際にはどこから来たのかというと、
Start this with many branches
多くのブランチから始める
The bone grains are few and hard
骨の粒が少なくて硬い
Until now its branches have become few
今までその支店は少なくなりました
basically a trunk
基本的にはトランク
Then what about the corn produced
では、生産されたトウモロコシはどうでしょうか
This becomes a big bone
これが大きな骨になります
So reducing the branches increases the size of the bone grain
したがって、枝を減らすと骨粒のサイズが大きくなります
So is the rice
お米もそうですよ
This rice is a very important grain
このお米はとても大切な穀物です
Then our main fairy is very smart
それから、私たちのメインの妖精はとても賢いです
In this I just started talking about
この中で私はちょうど話し始めたところですが、
The Lord Immortal breathes there
不滅の主がそこで息をしている
Then maybe take the day...
それなら、一日かかるかもしれません...
to the water's edge
水に行く
just see the water
ただ水を見てください
grow a certain plant
ある植物を育てる
Most other plants do not grow
他のほとんどの植物は成長しません
only it is long
ただ長いです
it has encouragement
それはまだ励みになります
This is the origin of rice
これがお米の原点です
But the encouragement at that time
でもその時の励ましは
fall off easily
簡単に落ちる
then fall into the water
その後水に落ちます
to the plant itself
植物そのものに
it is said that encouragement falls off easily
励ましは落ちやすいと言われます
it breeds easily
簡単に繁殖します
Just now Vice President Wang also introduced
先ほど王副主席も紹介しました
the rice seed
米の種
able to germinate in water
水中でも発芽できる
is a very special phenomenon
非常に特殊な現象です
Including corn, wheat, barley, sorghum, etc.
トウモロコシ、小麦、大麦、ソルガムなどを含みます。
those plants
それらの植物
Seeds cannot germinate in water
種子は水中では発芽しない
rice is ok
ご飯は大丈夫です
It has such characteristics
このような特徴を持っています
while our ancestors
一方私たちの先祖は
Take advantage of this characteristic to grow rice
この特性を活かしたお米作り
Because it can control weeds
雑草を抑制できるので
Most other plants are not tolerant to flooding
他のほとんどの植物は洪水に耐えられません
So my rice is planted in water
私の米は水の中に植えられています
i stand alone
私は独りで立ちます
no one competes with me
誰も私と競争しません
our ancestors
私たちの先祖
so why come to us
それでなぜ私たちのところに来るのですか
where are we now
私たちは今どこにいますか
grow rice
稲を育てる
You can see the rice is still planted in this water
まだこの水の中に稲が植えられているのがわかります
Weed control is a big reason
雑草対策が大きな理由
The main reason is not that rice really likes water
主な理由は、お米が本当に水が好きなわけではありません
Water actually has some effect on root growth
実は水は根の成長にある程度の影響を与えます
So during certain growing periods
したがって、特定の成長期には
It makes the rice grow well
お米がよく育ちます
it drains the water
それは水を排出します
But usually it makes it flood
でも普通は洪水になるよ
Because it can control weeds
雑草を抑制できるので
This way you don't need to spend artificial weeding
そうすれば人工的な除草に費用をかける必要がなくなります
Or sprinkle this weed spray
もしくはこの除草スプレーをまいてください
Because weed is expensive
雑草は高価なので
Weed spray is the world's
除草スプレーは世界
In the chemicals used in agriculture
農業で使用される化学物質の中で
most
量最多的
That rice has this benefit
あのお米にはこんな効能がある
But the disadvantage is that
しかし、欠点は、
You're going to go if you're so familiar with it.
そんなに詳しいなら行きますよ。
you can really receive
本当に受け取ることができます
there is not much to eat
食べるものがあまりない
So what about our taro seeds?
では、タロイモの種はどうでしょうか？
In the end it will be able to grow into this rice
最終的にはこのお米に育つでしょう
Its bone grains are tightly combined with the rice fragments
骨粒が米片としっかりと結合している
not easy to drop
落とすのは簡単ではない
Then it's easy for us
それなら私たちにとっては簡単です
Good for our harvest
私たちの収穫に良い
Okay, what about Mr. Yu, for thousands of years
さて、ユウさんはどうですか、何千年もの間
Going west is a very complicated process
西へ行くのは非常に複雑なプロセスだ
Then we use this IR
次に、この IR を使用します
The Philippine International Pirate Research Center
フィリピン国際海賊研究センター
They yu come out IR 64
IR 64 出てきますね
From this breed
この品種から
we don't need much explanation
多くの説明は必要ありません
What does the eyebrows mean?
眉毛にはどんな意味があるのでしょうか？
but he meant
しかし彼が言いたかったのは
he has many ancestors
彼にはたくさんの先祖がいる
Then each of these frames is an ancestor
したがって、これらの各フレームは祖先になります。
his mother father
彼の母親 父親
Then he goes to crossbred
それから彼は交配に行きます
After this is handed over to this
これをこれに引き継いだ後
offspring with another
他人との子孫
so don't pay
だから払わないでください
What about the hybridization process?
ハイブリダイゼーションのプロセスについてはどうですか？
Elites will mutate
エリートは変異するだろう
there will be missing
欠けているだろう
there will be reorganization
再編があるだろう
He keeps changing
彼は変わり続ける
So he later encountered these waterway species
そこで彼は後にこれらの水路種に遭遇しました
With this ancestor all already have appearance above
この祖先では、すべてがすでに上記の外観を持っています
Many agronomic traits above
上記の多くの農業形質
have very different characteristics.
非常に異なる特性を持っています。
Therefore, Mr. Yu, a human being, has been
したがって、人間であるユウさんは、
Constantly changing the elite of this plant
この工場のエリートは常に変更されています
This particle is the taro seed of this wheat
この粒はこの小麦のタロイモの種です
The different strains of wheat it compares to each other
小麦のさまざまな品種を比較する
Sorry, this is Brosica
ごめんなさい、ブロシカです
This is the cruciferous vegetable
これはアブラナ科の野菜です
In this particle, that is
この粒子では、つまり、
If you AA this breed
あなたがこの品種をAAするなら
Crossbreed with the BB breed
BB品種と交配する
its offspring becomes ab
その子孫はabになります
Then I mean cross BB with CC and it becomes BC
つまり、BBとCCをクロスさせるとBCになります。
have such characteristics
そのような特徴を持っています
So after crossing your chromosome
つまり、染色体を交差させた後、
it will start to mix
混ざり始めます
what's more
そのうえ
Because our taro breeders also know that
私たちのタロイモ飼育者もそれを知っているので、
increased number of chromosomes
染色体の数が増えた
These can often make your output come out of these
これらにより、出力がこれらから得られることがよくあります
bone or fruit
骨とか果物とか
its size will increase
そのサイズは大きくなります
So it figured out how to make its gene body bigger
そこで遺伝子本体を大きくする方法を考え出した
Then it may be three different main lines
その場合、それは 3 つの異なる主線になる可能性があります
it just mixes it up
それはそれを混ぜるだけです
or the same genetic
もしくは同じ遺伝子
it doubles it and triples it
それは2倍にも3倍にもなります
All sorts of ways this genetics can be used to do
この遺伝学を利用してあらゆる種類のことができる
So what about wheat? What about current wheat?
では、小麦はどうでしょうか、現在の小麦はどうでしょうか。
What about its genetics?
その遺伝子はどうなっているのでしょうか？
It can have the shape of three sets of chromosomes like this
このように 3 セットの染色体の形状を持つことができます。
Then we just mentioned that
それから、先ほども言いましたが、
Corn is being bred and it's encouraged to grow bigger
トウモロコシは品種改良されており、より大きくなるように奨励されています
why
なぜ
That's because breeders know that
ブリーダーはそれを知っているからです
hybrid vigor
ハイブリッドの活力
Then we humans are always like this
それでは私たち人間はいつもこうです
sometimes respectful breeding
時には敬意を持って繁殖する
You will feel that there may be some bad shape coming out
何か悪い形が出てくるかもしれないと感じるでしょう
So the more distant genetics
したがって、遺伝学が遠ければ遠いほど、
If you are far away and come here to get married
遠く離れていて結婚するためにここに来るなら
It's possible to be smarter after having a baby
赤ちゃんを産んだ後は賢くなる可能性がある
Said that when I was in high school
高校生の時に言ってた
Our relic teacher talks to us all day long
私たちの聖遺物の先生は一日中私たちに話しかけます
if you are taiwanese
あなたが台湾人なら
You'd better marry someone from the Northeast in the future
将来は東北人と結婚したほうがいいよ
Xinjiang people or something
新疆の人か何か
Advocate with us all day long
一日中私たちと一緒に擁護しましょう
Then he really insisted on genetic warfare
それから彼は本当に遺伝子戦争を主張した
it may be possible
それは可能かもしれない
Can have offspring that will be better
より優れた子孫を残すことができる
So this can be seen
それでこれを見ることができます
This corn, this A and B
このトウモロコシ、このAとB
It turns out that one may be the father and the other may be the mother.
一人が父親で、もう一人が母親である可能性があることが判明しました。
After he crossed
彼が渡った後
No matter how you hand over the seeds of his offspring
どうやって子孫の種を渡しても
become bigger
大きくなる
After the seeds grow bigger, after the encouragement grows bigger
種が大きくなってから 励ましが大きくなってから
The farmer's harvest began to increase
農家の収穫量が増え始めた
So what about this upgrade company?
では、アップグレード会社はどうでしょうか？
He started selling the offspring
彼は子孫を売り始めた
his offspring
彼の子孫
It is really better if the offspring are encouraged.
子孫が励まされるのは本当に良いことです。
But farmers can't breed by themselves
しかし、農家は自分たちで繁殖することはできません
because after you reproduce yourself
自分自身を再現した後だから
What about his offspring?
彼の子孫はどうなるのでしょうか？
Bad shape at the beginning will reappear
最初の悪い形が再発する
So what about this agricultural upgrading company in many international markets?
では、多くの国際市場で展開しているこの農業改良会社はどうでしょうか?
They're selling this hybrid seed
彼らはこのハイブリッド種子を販売しています
he makes money from it
彼はそれでお金を稼いでいます
He hybridized himself in the company
彼は社内で自分自身をハイブリッド化した
and sell the hybrid seed to farmers
そしてハイブリッド種子を農家に販売する
Farmers breed themselves
農家は自分たちで繁殖する
This seed is getting worse
この種は悪化している
This is the characteristic of corn
これがトウモロコシの特徴です
Because it is required for heterosis
ヘテローシスに必要なため
Then we usually grow rice by ourselves
それから私たちは普段自分たちでお米を育てています
Needless to say
言うまでもなく
I've been buying hybrid seeds
ハイブリッドの種子を購入しています
Because rice self-fertilizes
お米は自家受精するので
Its offspring can still grow well
その子孫はまだ元気に成長します
but actually hybrid
でも実はハイブリッド
even rice
米さえも
Its hybrid still has an advantage
ハイブリッドにはまだ利点がある
So on the mainland they are now
それで彼らは今本土にいるのです
What about this hybrid rice?
このハイブリッド米はどうでしょうか？
is very popular now
今とても人気があります
Because the output increased so much
生産量がかなり増えたので
It can be increased by more than 20 to 30%
20～30％以上増加する可能性があります
OK
OK
so what about farmers
では農家はどうでしょうか
I have to deal with this biotech company
このバイオテクノロジー企業と取引しなければならない
go buy this seed
この種を買いに行きます
Although more expensive
より高価ですが
cost money
お金がかかる
But because of its high yield
しかし、その収量が高いため、
So what about the statistics?
それでは統計はどうなのでしょうか？
I mean it came out in 1935
1935年に発売されたということですね
There is hybrid rice between 60 and
60と60の間のハイブリッドライスがあります
The hybrid rice planted by this farmer
この農家が植えたハイブリッド米
The area is getting higher and higher
エリアはどんどん高くなっていく
because it can make money
それはお金を稼ぐことができるからです
good
良い
OK
OK
Then let's come again, as mentioned earlier
それではまた来ましょう、先ほども言いましたが
Around 1960 to 2000
1960年から2000年頃
Our population has almost tripled
私たちの人口はほぼ3倍になりました
There is a very important reason for that
それにはとても重要な理由があります
What about that period?
その期間についてはどうでしょうか？
food has almost tripled
食料が3倍近くになった
That great contribution is the two scholars
その偉大な貢献は二人の学者です
One is Noven Borla
一人はノーベン・ボーラです
The other one is our Academician Zhang Deci
もう一人は私たちの学者、張徳慈です。
What about Noven, he is the boss of wheat
ノーベンはどうですか、彼は小麦のボスです
Academician Zhang Deci is the chief executive who makes rice
学者の張徳慈氏は米作りの最高責任者である
Where's the time for their boss?
上司の時間はどこにありますか?
In fact, it was about that time
実はその頃だったんですよ
What a pity for this Westerner
この西洋人はなんとも残念だ
always have an advantage in the comparison
比較において常に有利な立場にある
they won the nobel prize
彼らはノーベル賞を受賞した
But what about Academician Zhang?
しかし、張学者はどうでしょうか？
It's a pity I didn't get the Nobel Prize
ノーベル賞を受賞できなかったのは残念です
So yesterday Ang Lee won the best director
昨日、アン・リーが最優秀監督賞を受賞した
He is also very emotional
彼もとても感情的です
We orientals often have a lot of actors
私たち東洋人には俳優がたくさんいることが多い
are very good
とても良いです
inside this boy pie
このボーイパイの中に
That indian guy really did a really good job
あのインド人は本当に良い仕事をした
no awards were proposed
賞品は提案されませんでした
So the orientals are often at a disadvantage here
したがって、東洋人はここでは不利な立場にあることが多い
Academician Zhang is still a pity
張学者はやはり残念だ
Fortunately, there were many awards later.
幸いなことに、その後多くの賞を受賞しました。
Vatican Third World
バチカン第三世界
Then this has something like this and finally has this
次に、これは次のようなものになり、最終的にはこれになります
taylor award or something
テイラー賞か何か
In the end, they gave him a lot of honors.
最終的に、彼らは彼に多くの栄誉を与えました。
ok, what about their type of bath?
さて、お風呂の種類はどうですか？
The most important thing is that he made this wheat and corn
最も重要なことは、彼がこの小麦とトウモロコシを作ったことです
height reduction
高さを低くする
Why can the output be improved
なぜ出力が向上するのか
First
初め
when he grows too tall
彼が背が高くなりすぎるとき
is his nutrition
彼の栄養です
Much of his energy wasted on him
彼のエネルギーの多くは彼に費やされた
wasted in his constant vegetative reproduction
絶え間ない栄養生殖に無駄に費やされている
Then he won't understand
そうしたら彼は理解できないだろう
so you waste energy
だからエネルギーを浪費するんだよ
so you don't let him be so high
だから彼をそんなにハイにさせないでね
It can use a lot of energy on the seeds
種子に多くのエネルギーを使用する可能性があります
Besides, it's a little shorter
あと、少し短いです
It will have more branches
枝も増えるだろうし
Like rice and wheat
米や小麦のように
So its output will also increase
そうすると出力も上がります
that in addition
それに加えて
In fact, the first green revolution
実際、最初の緑の革命
Except for this dwarf variety
この矮性品種を除いて
the breed itself
品種自体
Another feature is that
もう一つの特徴は、
because we are doing
私たちがやってるから
We all need to be wet and fat when we are doing crops
農作物を作るとき、私たちは皆、濡れて太っている必要があります
Especially egg fat is very much needed
特に卵脂肪は非常に必要です
can increase its output
出力を増やすことができます
But you are getting fatter
でも君はどんどん太っていく
Rice is a plant that grows faster
お米は成長が早い植物です
higher
より高い
It's easy to fall like this
こうなると落ちやすいです
so you can see how tall it is
とても高いことがわかります
getting so short now
今ではとても短くなっています
It's easier to fall
落ちやすくなります
So what about after it is short?
では、短くなった後はどうなるでしょうか？
You can fatten up a little more
もう少し太ってもいいよ
So it can increase its output
したがって、出力を増やすことができます
So what about these two crops?
では、これら 2 つの作物はどうでしょうか?
are very similar
都非常的像
very similar method
非常によく似た方法
that's it
それでおしまい
that's important
それは重要です
this in several countries
これはいくつかの国で
or an indian
またはインド人
This is a lot of people
これはたくさんの人です
The original food is not enough
オリジナルの食事だけでは物足りない
But he planted this
でも彼はこれを植えました
After half-milk wheat
半乳小麦の後
In fact, after the crop dwarfs,
実際、作物が矮小化した後、
Its disease resistance will also be improved
耐病性も向上します
What about its output?
その出力はどうなるのでしょうか？
improved a lot
かなり改善されました
Since it originally had to import food
元々は食料を輸入していたので、
become it able to output this food
この食べ物をアウトプットできるようになる
so this is the first time
だからこれが初めてです
A very important contribution of the green revolution
緑の革命の非常に重要な貢献
So is the rice
お米もそうですよ
So in this paragraph
したがって、この段落では
The period from 1960 to 2000
1960年から2000年までの期間
double the population
人口を2倍にする
From 3 billion to 6 billion
30億から60億へ
Rice production is also
お米の生産も
You see this is double this
わかりますか、これはこの2倍です
2 to 4 this
2～4本
every year to every stew
毎年、どのシチューにも
The amount that can be produced per project
1プロジェクトあたりの生産可能量
Academician Zhang
張学者
what is he doing amazingly
彼は驚くべきことをしているのですか
This special waterway in Taiwan
台湾の特別な水路
low foot stain fried
ローフットステインフライ
take it to the philippines
フィリピンに持って行こう
Hybridized with this local waterway in the Philippines
フィリピンの地元水路とハイブリッド
pre-out this IR-8
このIR-8のプリアウト
IR-8
IR-8
this rice
このお米
Known as Miracle Rice
奇跡のお米と呼ばれる
because of its output
その出力のせいで
just make it double like this
このように二重にするだけです
So this one is very famous
それで、これはとても有名です
This is a species of waterway
これは水路の一種です
that's amazing
それはすごいです
The whole world knows that it is from Taiwan
台湾発であることは世界中に知られています
low foot stain fried
ローフットステインフライ
So also like our Director Ang Lee
アン・リー監督も同様です
Sell ​​Taiwan to countries all over the world
台湾を世界各国に売り込む
OK
OK
So during this period of the Green Revolution
つまり、緑の革命のこの時期に
You can see that the population is actually increasing
実際に人口が増えていることがわかります
it this
それこの
Different colors refer to different states
異なる色は異なる状態を表します
We can start by marking which state
どの状態をマークすることから始めますか
Asia is the most
アジアが一番
The population is increasing the most
人口が一番増えてるのは
The population increased by one hundred percent
人口は100パーセント増加した
Food has also increased by more than one hundred percent
食料も100パーセント以上増加しました
But the cultivated area
しかし耕作地は
In fact, you can see that the line is very slow
実際、回線が非常に遅いことがわかります。
Is this right? It’s faster to climb uphill than this one.
そうですか？これより上り坂を登るほうが早いです。
this is very calm
これはとても穏やかです
It only increases the cultivated area by 20 percent
耕作面積が20パーセント増えるだけだ
So it means the output of grain per unit area
つまり、単位面積当たりの穀物の生産高を意味します
increased very much
とても増えた
Then this is its species
それならこれがその種です
great place
すばらしい所
OK, let's finish this traditional breeding
OK、この伝統的な繁殖は終わりにしましょう
let's talk
話しましょう
How does modern breeding work
現代の育種はどのように行われているのか
What about modern molecular breeding?
現代の分子育種はどうでしょうか？
allows us to increase efficiency
効率を高めることができます
it combines molecular biology
分子生物学を組み合わせたものです
and tissue culture
そして組織培養
Then there's the part-time job
あとはアルバイトですね
so breeding
だから繁殖する
It's not that modern technology
現代のテクノロジーがあるわけではない
Tradition is gone
伝統は消えた
In fact, we still have to solve it now
実はまだ解決されていない
together
一緒
We have produced many varieties in the laboratory
研究室では多くの品種を生産しています
to plant in the field
畑に植える
still rely on many agronomists in the field
今でもこの分野の多くの農学者に依存しています
Specologists come and continue to help us
スペロジストが来て私たちを助け続けます
care for and reproduce these offspring
これらの子孫を世話し、繁殖させます
Then this technological progress
それから、この技術の進歩は、
Advances in molecular biotechnology are very important
分子バイオテクノロジーの進歩は非常に重要です
because each of us
なぜなら私たち一人一人が
including human animals or this crop
人間の動物やこの作物を含む
we have a genotype
私たちは遺伝子型を持っています
That is to say, inside our chromosomes
つまり、私たちの染色体の中には、
have a lot of genes
遺伝子をたくさん持っている
So it will determine our phenotype
それが私たちの表現型を決定するでしょう
Decide what we'll look like when the time comes
その時が来たら私たちがどのようになるかを決めてください
So everyone's genes are a little bit different
つまり、みんなの遺伝子は少しずつ異なります
So the length is not the same
なので長さは同じではありません
but in
しかし、中で
you have to tell
言わなければなりません
Which gene causes which phenotype
どの遺伝子がどの表現型を引き起こすか
Genotype is relatively easy to use scientific methods to identify
遺伝子型は科学的手法を使用して比較的簡単に特定できます
Phenotyping is more difficult
表現型はさらに難しい
because this
なぜならこれは
just say one parent
片方の親とだけ言ってください
Just say a mom and dad
お父さんとお母さんって言ってください
You know the baby you gave birth to
あなたはあなたが産んだ赤ちゃんを知っています
gave birth to three children five children
3人の子供5人の子供を産んだ
Everyone basically looks different
基本的にみんな見た目が違う
less likely to say exactly the same
全く同じことを言う可能性は低い
besides being twins
双子であること以外に
So, genes are complicated
つまり、遺伝子は複雑なのです
just a little difference
ほんの少しの違い
Then he's likely to come out with a different phenotype.
そうすればまた違う表現タイプが出てくるかも知れません。
so we
だから私たちは
but for us
しかし私たちにとっては
we grow crops in the field
私たちは畑で作物を育てます
phenotype is important
表現型は重要です
I just need my good breed
私に必要なのは私の良い品種だけです
looks like this
このように見えます
the output is so high
出力がとても高い
it is so delicious
とてもおいしいです
and you
あなたも
But your descendants are swollen and swollen
しかし、あなたの子孫はますます膨れ上がっています
After his father and mother interbreed with his mother
父親と母親が母親と交配した後
how do i know who is good
誰が良い人かをどうやって知ることができますか
who is bad
誰が悪いのか
So what about molecular biology?
では、分子生物学はどうでしょうか？
just let us
たださせてください
Help us do this breeding
この繁殖に協力してください
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
There is a variety of tomato
トマトにも色々な種類があります
it is a very good variety
とても良い品種です
may have large fruit
大きな実がなるかもしれない
high output
高出力
but it is not disease resistant
しかし耐病性はない
there's a bad breed in the wild
野生には悪い品種がいます
Or people don't pay much attention to his breed
あるいは、人々は彼の品種にあまり注意を払っていません
He actually has a disease resistance gene
実は病気に強い遺伝子を持っている
So our
それで私たちの
his chromosomes
彼の染色体
We now use different colors to represent
今ではさまざまな色を使って表現しています
And this bad tomato
そしてこのまずいトマト
disease resistance gene
耐病性遺伝子
It's the yellow one
黄色いのです
it's his genes
それは彼の遺伝子です
So what do we want to do with his good genes?
それでは、私たちは彼の優れた遺伝子をどうしたいのでしょうか?
disease resistance gene
耐病性遺伝子
Lead to this excellent tomato variety
この優れたトマト品種を導き出す
we are going to interbreed
私たちは交配するつもりです
What about after hybridization?
ハイブリダイゼーション後はどうなるでしょうか？
There will be many descendants
子孫もたくさんいるだろう
of various ages
さまざまな年齢の
then you don't know
それならあなたは知りません
Who is really carrying this disease resistance gene?
この病気耐性遺伝子を本当に持っているのは誰ですか?
what about that
そのことについて何
how to distinguish
見分ける方法
But of course you have someone to say
でももちろん言いたい人はいる
When you are in the field, you vaccinate him.
現場にいるときは、彼にワクチンを接種します。
Just sprinkle a bunch of sick bacteria on it.
そこに大量の病原菌を振りかけるだけです。
and see who survives
そして誰が生き残るか見てみましょう
But sometimes we don't like it
でも時にはそれが気に入らないこともある
Because we are in the field
私たちは現場にいるので
We're all terrified of these sick germs
私たちは皆、これらの病原菌を恐れています
You're going to scatter a bunch of sick germs down there again.
またそこに大量の病原菌をまき散らすことになるでしょう。
That patient's bacteria will never end in the future
その患者の細菌は今後もなくなることはない
So now there is a more scientific way to do
そこで、より科学的な方法が登場しました。
The most important thing is that after hybridization of this breed
最も重要なことは、この品種の交雑後、
its descendants
その子孫
we can all say this
私たちは皆これを言うことができます
its different offspring
その異なる子孫
Some people have the gene of this father
この父親の遺伝子を持っている人もいる
disease resistance gene
耐病性遺伝子
there is no
ありません
Some have mother's genes
母親の遺伝子を持っている人もいる
But you can see it has different combinations
しかし、さまざまな組み合わせがあることがわかります
So how do I tell who is good?
では、誰が優れているかをどうやって見分ければよいのでしょうか？
Then we're going to use this genetic marker to filter
次に、この遺伝マーカーを使用してフィルタリングします
This disease-resistant spider
この病気に強いクモ
the molecular biology approach
分子生物学的アプローチ
allows us to judge
私たちが判断できるようになります
every plant
すべての植物
who has our disease resistance genes
私たちの病気耐性遺伝子を持っているのは誰ですか
Then I put it with
それから私はそれを付けました
this one good this one mom
これはいい、これはお母さん
or this species
あるいはこの種
We keep backcrossing and backcrossing
私たちは戻し交配を繰り返します
Of course humans can't do that.
もちろん人間にはそんなことはできません。
But plants can
しかし、植物にはそれができます
We can go back and forth
行ったり来たりできるよ
take it this one
これを取ってください
This gene from a bad breed
この遺伝子は悪い品種から生まれました
dilute until then
それまでに薄める
diluted to the end
最後まで薄められた
Then only this disease resistance gene remains
するとこの耐病性遺伝子だけが残る
Everything else is the gene of this good breed
それ以外はすべてこの良い品種の遺伝子です
so what
だから何
This is still using our current technology
これはまだ現在の技術を使用しています
This can now be accelerated
これを加速できるようになりました
But when there was no such method before
しかし、以前はそのような方法がなかったとき、
A lot of them are really groping in the field.
彼らの多くは本当に野原を手探りしているのです。
So it takes a very long time
なのでとても時間がかかります
Likely five years, seven years, eight years, ten years
おそらく5年、7年、8年、10年かかるでしょう
But now we are really at the time of everyone's food
でも今は本当にみんなの食事の時期です
Really need fear
本当に恐怖が必要だ
Sometimes it feels like five or ten years is really a long wait
5年や10年待つのは本当に長いように感じることがある
Then use the method now
それでは、今すぐこのメソッドを使用してください
About three to five years
3年から5年くらい
A good variety can be predicted
良い品種が予測できる
much faster
はるかに高速
That's why
それが理由です
But what about this molecular biology approach?
しかし、この分子生物学的アプローチはどうでしょうか?
How can we
どうしたらいいの
How about identifying its genotype?
その遺伝子型を特定してみてはどうでしょうか？
We need to understand its entire genetic structure
その遺伝子構造全体を理解する必要がある
So many works
たくさんの作品
like strawberry grapes, cotton, papaya
イチゴ、ブドウ、綿、パパイヤなど
There are also jade mud, snow rice, soybeans like this
こんなヒスイ泥、雪米、大豆もあります
This rapeseed waits for many trees
この菜種はたくさんの木を待ちます
Now its genes are slowly being unraveled
今、その遺伝子が徐々に解明されつつある
So we're doing this molecular bath
それで私たちはこの分子風呂をやっています
help will be great
助けてくれるでしょう
OK, so this is a traditional bath swelling
OK、これは伝統的なお風呂の腫れです
Combining some techniques of modern molecular biology
現代の分子生物学のいくつかの技術を組み合わせる
But basically there's no genetic engineering involved
しかし、基本的に遺伝子工学は関与していません
None of the stuff we just talked about has been genetically engineered.
私たちが今話したものはどれも遺伝子組み換えではありません
But the method just mentioned
しかし、先ほど述べた方法では、
It still takes a little longer
まだ少し時間がかかります
That flower is still a bit more labor-intensive
あの花はまだもう少し手間がかかる
So it's time to move on to this genetically engineered swelling technique
そこで、この遺伝子組み換えの腫れ技術に移る時が来ました。
It can improve efficiency and accuracy
効率と精度を向上させることができます
that's safer
その方が安全です
We will talk about this later
これについては後で話します
As we said just now, there is this excellent tomato variety
先ほども言いましたが、素晴らしいトマトの品種があります。
That bad tomato variety has this disease-resistant gene.
あの悪いトマト品種は、この病気に強い遺伝子を持っています。
Now our molecular biology only needs me to know what kind of gene this gene is
さて、私たちの分子生物学は、この遺伝子がどのような種類の遺伝子であるかを知ることだけを必要としています。
I have a way to copy it out
コピーする方法があります
and insert it into this variety
この品種に挿入します
At present, most people plug in at will.
現時点では、ほとんどの人が自由に接続しています。
But it doesn't matter as long as you don't destroy its original important genes
でも、本来の重要な遺伝子を破壊しない限りは問題ない
But technology is constantly improving
しかしテクノロジーは常に進歩しています
Now there are technologies that can be very accurate
今では非常に正確な技術が存在します
Where am I on the chromosome
私は染色体のどこにいますか
I want to insert it in that position
その位置に挿入したい
I know that location has the influence of this plant is the most
場所がこの植物の影響を最も大きく受けていることはわかっています
can do this now
今すぐこれができます
So this is the genetic engineering method
これが遺伝子組み換え手法です
It can do this very efficiently and accurately.
これを非常に効率的かつ正確に行うことができます。
Because of our traditional method of hybridization
当社の伝統的なハイブリダイゼーション手法により、
It will bring a lot of bad genes
悪い遺伝子をたくさん持ち込むことになる
So you have to keep crossing back
だからあなたはまた渡り続けなければなりません
take a long time
長い時間がかかります
But often in the end
でも最終的には多くの場合
still have a little gene
まだ遺伝子が少し残っている
you can't help it maybe bad genes
仕方ないけど遺伝子が悪いのかもしれない
not easy to rule it out
それを排除するのは簡単ではない
Often there will still be such problems
多くの場合、依然としてそのような問題が発生します
But now we have a very precise method
しかし今、私たちは非常に正確な方法を持っています
You can avoid this problem by inserting
を挿入することでこの問題を回避できます。
what's another advantage
もう一つの利点は何ですか
We know that there are many types of this grain
この穀物には多くの種類があることがわかっています
From fruits, vegetables, bones, beans, etc.
果物、野菜、骨、豆などから
there are so many different crops
非常に多くの異なる作物があります
In fact, there are often some genes
実際には、いくつかの遺伝子が存在することがよくあります。
good genes like
良い遺伝子のような
As I just said, I am so watery that I have a gene for resistance to flooding
先ほども言いましたが、私は水が多いの​​で洪水に強い遺伝子を持っています。
But other bone types are not submerged
ただし、他の種類の骨は沈みません。
Can I put my gene in corn
自分の遺伝子をトウモロコシに入れてもいいですか
put in the wheat
小麦を入れます
no
いいえ
because they can't fry
揚げられないから
but we will know
しかし、私たちは知るでしょう
what kind of gene is this
これはどのような遺伝子ですか
Can control this apricot after
このアプリコットを制御できるのは次のとおりです
I can turn water into the flood tolerance gene
水を洪水耐性遺伝子に変えることができる
do put
入れてください
corn or wheat
トウモロコシまたは小麦
That corn is more drought-resistant than baby corn
そのトウモロコシはベビーコーンよりも乾燥に強い
it can have a gene for drought resistance
乾燥に強い遺伝子を持っている可能性がある
we can put it in the waterway
水路に入れることができます
Relying on traditional jade seed hybridization is not enough
従来のヒスイ種子交雑に依存するだけでは十分ではありません
Because different species can't interbreed
異なる種は交配できないから
So I rely on the method of molecular biology
そこで私は分子生物学の手法に頼る
I can put the drought tolerance gene in corn
トウモロコシに乾燥耐性遺伝子を組み込むことができる
I put it in the waterway
水路に入れてみた
That doesn't matter
そんなことは関係ない
Although people say that you are artificial
人造人間だと言われても
You mix this gene like this
この遺伝子をこのように混ぜ合わせると
Will there be any problems in nature
自然界に何か問題はあるのでしょうか
Actually it's okay
実際は大丈夫です
look at us
私たちを見て
Anyway, these grains are eaten in the stomach
とにかく、これらの穀物は胃の中で食べられます
It's all mixed together, right?
全部混ざってますよね？
No matter where you came from
どこから来たとしても
So you are from wheat
それであなたは小麦出身です
From corn to vegetables
トウモロコシから野菜へ
In our stomach
私たちのお腹の中で
There are a lot of different grains under finance
金融の下にはさまざまな穀物がたくさんあります
It doesn't matter if it's mixed in the stomach
お腹の中で混ざっても大丈夫
More importantly, it will be digested at all
さらに重要なのは、それは完全に消化されることです
no matter what food you eat
どんな食べ物を食べても
it digests you absorb it
それは消化します、あなたはそれを吸収します
So this gene of this different species
つまり、この異なる種のこの遺伝子は
It's actually a good thing to exchange like this
本当はこうやってやりとりするのが良いんだよ
That is also true for this natural world
それはこの自然界にも当てはまります
It doesn't matter too much.
あまり関係ありません。
As we said earlier
先ほども言ったように
The human race is already a lot of genes
人類はすでにたくさんの遺伝子を持っています
I've been messing around like this
こうやってごちゃごちゃしてました
OK let's give an example
OK、例を挙げてみましょう
with this genetic engineering method
この遺伝子組み換え手法を使って
what can we do
私たちは何ができる
in africa
アフリカで
This bacterial tail vulture disease
この細菌性尾ハゲワシ病
is very serious
とても深刻です
Farmers often don't get the bananas
農家はバナナを手に入れられないことが多い
Bananas in countries like Africa
アフリカのような国のバナナ
is an important food crop
重要な食用作物です
If so
もしそうなら
I was already short of food
すでに食料が不足していました
That's going to make me hungry
それはお腹が空くよ
What about the bacteria?
細菌についてはどうですか？
After you cut the fungus
菌をカットしたら
you can see
見ることができます
stay with this sticky thing
この粘着物と一緒にいてください
this is bacteria
これは細菌です
So it's a terrible disease
だから恐ろしい病気なんです
no good treatment
良い治療はありません
Traditional encounters are also very limited
従来の出会いも非常に限られています
But now I know that green peppers contain
でも今はピーマンに含まれていることを知りました。
there is this chili inside
中にはこの唐辛子が入っています
There is a gene that is resistant to this disease
この病気に強い遺伝子がある
So put it in this banana
だからこのバナナに入れて
Look no, then go get vaccinated
ノーとわかったらワクチン接種を受けましょう
Of course, this is done in a laboratory or a greenhouse.
もちろん、これは実験室または温室で行われます。
It turns out that once you are vaccinated with this species, you are sightseeing.
この種のワクチンを接種すると、観光できるようになることが判明しました。
But this one has the gene from the pepper
しかし、これはコショウの遺伝子を持っています
it can grow well
それはよく成長することができます
So this is a great one for genetic engineering
これは遺伝子工学にとって素晴らしいものです
a contribution
貢献
so now in africa
だから今アフリカにいる
Bananas like this have already started
こんなバナナがもう始まっています
They are evaluating whether it is possible for farmers to plant
彼らは農家が作付け可能かどうかを評価している
Another example
もう一つの例
It is an antibacterial virus using this thule bacteria
このトゥーレ菌を利用した抗菌ウイルスです
antimicrobial protein we should talk about antimicrobial protein
抗菌タンパク質 抗菌タンパク質について話すべきです
Suriella is a bacterium
スリエラは細菌です
In fact it is in our
実際、それは私たちの中にあります
It has been used in agriculture for a long time
古くから農業に使われてきた
It has been used for decades
何十年も使われてきた
because it kills a lot of that
それは多くのことを殺すからです
Insects like this
こんな虫も
Insects like many oysters and butterflies
昆虫は多くのカキや蝶が好き
will harm the forest
森に害を与えるだろう
What about in the forest?
森の中ではどうでしょうか？
You're less likely to get sprayed sometimes
時々スプレーされる可能性が低くなります
Because the cost is too high
コストが高すぎるため
and sometimes limited
そして時には制限される
that could hurt a lot
それはとても傷つくかもしれない
the hesitant animals
ためらう動物たち
So Suriella is used in this forest
この森ではスリエラが使われているので
I used to be a biological house
私は以前は生物学的な家でした
It's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
Then people who grow organic vegetables now
では、今有機野菜を育てている人たち
Actually used a lot
実はよく使っている
he is on top of his vegetables
彼は野菜の上にいます
on top of the fruits and vegetables
果物や野菜の上に
He still kills Suriella
彼はまだスリエラを殺します
Really ask this organic heavier person to know
この有機的に重い人に知ってもらいましょう
Those biotech companies
それらのバイオテクノロジー企業
They took a gene in this suri bacterium
彼らはこのスリ菌の遺伝子を取り込みました
this gene it is to a
この遺伝子は、
insect-resistant protein
耐虫性タンパク質
it puts it in this corn
それをこのトウモロコシの中に入れます
you can see this corn
このトウモロコシが見えます
Without doing genetic engineering like this
こんな遺伝子組み換えをしなくても
This insect is very powerful
この虫はとても強いです
It's easy to destroy this corn just like that
このトウモロコシをそのまま壊すのは簡単だ
it just takes a few bites
ほんの数口食べるだけです
Farmers can't sell
農家は売れない
OK
OK
so what
だから何
The protein produced by this green machine
このグリーンマシンによって生成されるタンパク質
what kind of protein
どのようなタンパク質ですか
it this is its bacteria
これはその細菌です
visible under a microscope
顕微鏡で見える
Seen under a high powered microscope
高性能顕微鏡で観察
traditional method
伝統的な手法
You just put this threophyte
このスレオファイトを置くだけです
sprinkled on the surface of the leaves
葉の表面に振りかける
current genetic engineering methods
現在の遺伝子工学手法
is to let the plant itself produce this protein
植物自身にこのタンパク質を生成させることです
insects eat
虫が食べる
eat into the stomach
胃に食べる
either way
どちらにしても
it eats into the stomach
それは胃に食い込みます
the insect
昆虫
Insects like Lin Akagi
赤城リンのような昆虫
There are some skinny in its stomach
お腹には痩せた部分がいくつかあります
Its body will bind to this protein
その体はこのタンパク質に結合します
Then its stomach will be perforated by it
そうすれば胃に穴が開けられるだろう
So the insect's stomach and intestines are perforated
つまり、昆虫の胃と腸には穴が開いています
so why does this insect die
ではなぜこの虫は死ぬのか
Then its life body is a very special life body
そうすると、その生命体は非常に特別な生命体です
not all insects have
すべての昆虫が持っているわけではありません
Mainly because of the red wood insects
主に赤い木の昆虫のせいで
Then our people will not have such a life
そうすれば我が国の人々はそのような生活を送らなくなるでしょう
So it's harmless to people
なので人体には無害です
So why biocontrol
ではなぜ生物防除なのか
the reason it takes so long
こんなに時間がかかる理由
So those biotech companies
つまり、それらのバイオテクノロジー企業は
It puts this gene into this plant
この遺伝子をこの植物に導入します
let it produce itself
それ自体を生み出しましょう
That way you don't have to spray
そうすればスプレーする必要がなくなります
Because if you spray it, you still need to feed the bacteria
スプレーしてもバクテリアに餌を与える必要があるため
Then you have to spray it manually
そして手動でスプレーします
It takes energy and manpower
エネルギーと人手がかかる
Then another one has a potential problem
次に、別のものに潜在的な問題があります
Many people like organic vegetables and think they are safe
有機野菜が好きで安全だと思っている人が多い
Just wash and wash
ただ洗って洗うだけ
In fact, there may be a lot of bacteria still attached to it.
実際には、まだ多くの細菌が付着している可能性があります。
because of U.S
米国のせいで
We usually cook this food
私たちはいつもこの料理を作ります
in order to be able to truly completely sterilize
完全に殺菌できるようになる
So sometimes you spray the bacteria directly
したがって、場合によっては細菌に直接スプレーすることもあります
not necessarily a good thing
必ずしも良いことではない
But this protein
しかしこのプロテイン、
This is proved by experiments
これは実験によって証明されています
It is low enough that it is not harmful to humans
微量なので人体に害はありません
But it's enough to kill the insect
でも虫を殺すには十分だ
So this product in this genetic engineering
つまり、この遺伝子工学によるこの製品は
to be listed
リストされる
So it was very successful on corn
トウモロコシでは大成功でした
This genetic modification of us is called a gene
私たちのこの遺伝子組み換えは遺伝子と呼ばれます
Corn is not genetic
トウモロコシは遺伝的ではない
This is the blade just is it's into the blade
これが刃です、刃に入っているだけです
Then wrap it in this broken piece
それからこの壊れた部分で包みます
for farmers
農家向け
It is really expensive to buy this seed
この種を買うのは本当に高い
but its harvest is good
しかしその収穫は良い
Okay so that means he can make money
なるほど、つまり彼はお金を稼げるということですね
So why actually plant this genetically engineered plant like this
では、なぜ実際にこのように遺伝子組み換えされた植物を植えるのか
The country of these products
これらの製品の国
In fact, more and more farmers
実際、農家は増えています。
we'll come back later
後で戻ってきます
what good does he do
彼は何の役に立つのですか
Like this one that itself will resist insects
これ自体が昆虫に抵抗するもののように
What are the benefits of genetic crops
遺伝子作物の利点は何ですか
Then there are many people who say
そうすると、こう言う人も多いです
especially environmental groups
特に環境団体
I have always been very opposed to a product like this
私はこのような製品にはいつも反対していました
But this is in Australia
でもここはオーストラリアです
They were in 1993 and 1994
それらは1993年と1994年でした
I think he is starting to do
彼がやり始めているのがわかります
This dotted line is the genetic cotton
この点線が遺伝子綿です
He started in 1996 and 1997 to 2002 and 2003
彼は 1996 年と 1997 年から 2002 年と 2003 年まで活動を開始しました。
During the 56 years
56年間
He went to see the amount of pesticide used
彼は農薬の使用量を見に行った
So to achieve this one is the traditional cotton
これを実現するのが伝統的なコットンです
The following is genetic cotton
以下は遺伝子綿です
Its usage is reduced by one-third to one-half
使用量が3分の1から2分の1に減ります
This is a very significant difference
これは非常に重要な違いです
It's just Australia
まさにオーストラリアですね
In fact, there are many countries in the world
実際、世界にはたくさんの国があります
a lot of crops
たくさんの作物
These are the crops now
これらは今の作物です
Think about how much that pesticide can be reduced
どれだけ農薬を削減できるかを考えてみましょう
OK this is cotton
はい、これは綿です
And then there are often people who object to memories
そして、思い出に反対する人がよくいます
He said this is for those in the field
彼はこれは現場の人たちのためだと言いました
Intentional insects are socially harmful
意図的な昆虫は社会的に有害です
because a deliberate insect is likely to eat you this
故意の虫がこれを食べてしまう可能性が高いからです
Resistant corn
耐性トウモロコシ
cotton or this soybean
綿かこの大豆か
This intentional insect will die
この意図的な昆虫は死ぬでしょう
So this experiment was done in mainland China
つまり、この実験は中国本土で行われたのです
He did it for ten years
彼はそれを10年間やりました
2001 to 2011
2001年から2011年
Then he went to see the toothworm's natural enemy
それから彼は歯虫の天敵に会いに行きました
So his natural enemy is the zerg
つまり彼の天敵はザーグだ
What kind of whore, grass spirit?
何の売春婦だ、草の精霊？
Then this spider waits
それからこの蜘蛛が待っています
What about the red line?
赤い線はどうでしょうか？
The blue line is Gm has produced Bt
青い線は Gm が Bt を生成したことを示します
Bt is the protein that fights insects
Btは昆虫と戦うタンパク質です
This blue thread is Bt cotton
この青い糸はBtコットンです
The red is non-Bt cotton
赤は非Btコットンです
You can look at the trees of its predators
捕食者の木を見ることができます
in different years
違う年に
its to overlap
重なることです
The curves all overlap
曲線はすべて重なっています
So the trees that say it's intentional insects are the same
つまり、故意の虫だと言っている木も同じだ
But this green one is the cotton of Bt Aircraft Flame
でもこの緑色のものはBt Aircraft Flameのコットンです
It's going to spray this sand bug spray
この砂虫スプレーを噴射します
so this blue this is no sandblast
この青はサンドブラストではありません
But but you don't have sand spray
でもでも、サンドスプレーを持っていない
It's cotton is probably also harvested
綿も収穫されているのでしょう
Because the insects probably ate it up
たぶん虫に食べられてしまったので
But the machine flame is that it can resist insects
でも機械の炎は虫を防ぐことができるということ
it doesn't need to be sprayed
スプレーする必要はありません
Then it farmers can also have a harvest
そうすれば農家も収穫できる
But if the plane is in flames, you go spray sand insecticide
でも、もし飛行機が炎上していたら、砂用の殺虫剤をスプレーしに行くんだよ
Although sandworms can
サンドワームは可能ですが、
But you can see the trees of its intentional insects are greatly reduced
しかし、意図的に昆虫が生息する木が大幅に減少しているのがわかります。
The number of crab worms and tooth worms
カニムシと歯ムシの数
You can see this non-myositic cotton
この非筋結性綿が見えます
hacking insecticide
ハッキング殺虫剤
It has so many toothworms
歯虫がたくさんいるよ
And this BT cotton or non-BT cotton
そしてこのBTコットンまたは非BTコットン
It's not sprayed
スプレーされてないよ
Its number of toothworms is very small
歯虫の数は非常に少ないです
so that means
つまり
It reduces the number of intentional insects
意図的な昆虫の数を減らします
But crab worms increase
でもカニムシが増える
In this non-BT this cotton
この非BTではこのコットン
in the case of pesticides
農薬の場合
so it's not just cotton
だから、ただのコットンではないのです
It's drizzled with some corn peanuts soy and all
トウモロコシ、ピーナッツ、大豆などをたっぷりかけてあります
both also benefit
都也受益
Because of the many toothworms it's
歯虫がたくさんいるので、
its this
それはこれです
Ancestor worship is very wide
祖先崇拝は非常に幅広い
it likes to eat many different crops
さまざまな作物を食べるのが好きです
So it drenches some
それで、それはいくらかびしょ濡れになります
That other crops also benefit
他の作物にも恩恵があること
So this was published last year on
それで、これは去年の日に出版されました
An article in Nature
Nature的一篇文章
good
良い
This we mentioned the crop of these experiences
これはこれらの経験の収穫について述べたものです
To be honest, it doesn't seem to have any impact on the environment.
正直に言うと、環境に影響を与えているようには見えません。
ok , then we will mention this again
わかりました、では、これについてはもう一度触れます
The issue we are concerned with is that
私たちが懸念している問題は、
The Gauge Challenges We Are Facing Now
私たちが今日直面しているゲージの課題
is how to produce enough food
十分な食料を生産する方法です
Come to remit a population of 9 billion
90億人の人口を送金しに来てください
this was just mentioned
これはちょうど言及されたばかりです
The population is now increasing at a rate that is rocketing upwards
人口は現在、右肩上がりの勢いで増加しています
The various activities of our human beings
私たち人間のさまざまな活動
for standard of living
生活水準のために
Then use the car
それなら車を使ってください
Then this uses a lot of machinery
それから、これはたくさんの機械を使います
wait a lot of carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素をたくさん待ってください
So it's this warming
それで、これは温暖化です
Also this keeps increasing
これも増え続けています
How can we do this without damaging the environment
環境にダメージを与えずにこれを行うにはどうすればよいでしょうか
It can also remit the global population
世界の人口を解放することもできる
it's a big challenge
それは大きな挑戦だ
can we not use robotic hands
ロボットハンドは使えないのか
use people to follow
人を使ってフォローする
It seems very difficult, labor is very expensive now
とても難しそうです、今は人件費がとても高いです
Our oil is also expensive
私たちのオイルも高価です
Harvest now with this machine
この機械で今すぐ収穫しましょう
Then carbon dioxide was produced
すると二酸化炭素が発生した
is that possible
それは可能ですか
no pesticides
農薬不使用
Because pesticides are not good for the environment
農薬は環境に良くないから
that won't work
それはうまくいきません
You can't harvest this
これでは収穫できません
but the man in the organic suit
でもオーガニックスーツを着た男は
This guy who promotes organic food
オーガニック食品を推進するこの人
He said yes, we can produce
彼は「はい、生産できます」と言いました
We just don't use pesticides
ただ農薬を使用していないだけです
But the problem is that the cost is very high
しかし、問題はコストが非常に高いことです
Why
なぜ
Because you have to use a lot of labor
多大な労力を使う必要があるため、
to catch bugs
虫を捕まえるために
to prevent
防ぐために
that's hard to mass produce
それは量産するのが難しい
its cost is high
そのコストは高いです
So this environment does not destroy
この環境が壊れないように
It is a dilemma to increase food
食料を増やすのはジレンマ
is a big challenge
大きな挑戦です
Then what's another question
それでは、もう一つの質問は何ですか
global land crisis
世界的な土地危機
Because our arable land area is actually getting smaller and smaller
なぜなら、実際に私たちの耕作可能な土地の面積はどんどん小さくなっているからです。
because of industrial development
産業の発展のせいで
There are many chemical pollution
化学汚染が多い
Industry brings a lot of chemicals
産業は多くの化学物質をもたらします
abnormal weather, floods, sweat disasters, etc.
異常気象、洪水、汗害など。
Then you can see that there are actually many land
そうすると、実際には土地がたくさんあることがわかります。
Constantly researching why
その理由を常に研究し続ける
Because we use a lot of fertilizer
肥料をたくさん使うので
Many fertilizers are useless
無駄な肥料が多い
no plant no absorption
植物がなければ吸収もありません
Then all combined on this soil
そして、すべてがこの土の上で組み合わされます
Then you have no water and no water
そうなると水も水もなくなる
Originally, the water could wash away a lot of fertilizers.
本来、水は多くの肥料を洗い流してしまう可能性があります。
but it lacks water
しかし水分が足りない
So all the crystals stay in the soil
つまりすべての結晶は土の中に残ります
In the case of serious research
本格的な研究の場合
This plant can't grow anymore
この植物はもう成長できません
You can see you are crying to death
あなたが死ぬほど泣いているのがわかります
Then desertification is the consequence of water shortage
砂漠化は水不足の結果である
Many countries have this problem
多くの国がこの問題を抱えています
Mainland This is the northern part of mainland China
Mainland 中国本土の北部です。
it lacks water and then deserts
水が不足すると砂漠になる
so they're going to plant grass
それで彼らは草を植えるつもりです
plant it with grass
草と一緒に植える
hope to reduce this one
これを減らすことを願っています
were able
できた
But there is a big problem, the sand leopard
しかし、大きな問題があります、スナヒョウ
Every year the dust leopard
毎年ダストヒョウ
It is because of the problem of desertification
砂漠化の問題だから
This population has increased
この人口は増えました
We already want to increase production and increase food production
私たちはすでに生産量を増やし、食料生産を増やしたいと考えています。
Land can be heavier and less and less
土地は重くなったり、どんどん小さくなったりする可能性があります
what to do
何をすべきか
When it comes to food, we must mention rice
食べ物といえばお米ですよね
Because rice is in all kinds of grains
お米にはいろいろな種類の穀物が入っているので、
inside the main food
メインフードの中に
It is 50% of the world's population
それは世界人口の50％です
a staple food
主食
Corn is the highest in terms of yield
トウモロコシは収量の点で最も高い
This is corn that is usually fed to our raw vinegar
通常、生酢に与えられるトウモロコシです。
Cows, pigs, sheep, etc.
牛、豚、羊など
So the real people eat mainly rice and wheat
つまり、現実の人々は主に米と小麦を食べています
Rice is the most important grain
米は最も重要な穀物です
ok so what
わかりました、それで何ですか
Since so many people eat rice
ご飯を食べる人が多いので
If you can increase the rice production
米の生産量を増やすことができれば
The importance of its impact like this
このようなインパクトの重要性
It can be shown
見せることができる
The global food
世界の食べ物
Because every country actually has a safety stock
実際にはどの国にも安全在庫があるからです
There will be anything from three months to six months
3ヶ月から6ヶ月まであります
Or more than half a year, one or two years
もしくは半年以上、1年か2年くらい
Different countries have different ways of doing this
国が異なればこれを行う方法も異なります
But let's look at the wheat, jade and soybeans
しかし、小麦、ヒスイ、大豆を見てみましょう
The period from 1975 to this 2016
1975年から今年2016年までの期間
Of course it's not that time yet
もちろんまだその時期ではない
It's about 2005 now
今は2005年くらいですかね
Its statistics are up to that time
統計はその時点までのものです
You can see it this safety stock
この安全在庫を見ればわかります
These three very important crops
この 3 つの非常に重要な作物
Because wheat is originally eaten
小麦は本来食べられるものなので
This jade is eaten by animals
この翡翠は動物に食べられます
Soybeans are eaten by both humans and animals
大豆は人間にも動物にも食べられる
Its safety stock has actually been at its lowest point all the time.
実際、安全在庫は常に最低水準にあります。
And it's jade mushroom
そして翡翠キノコです
Jade mushroom will still be very low
ヒスイキノコはまだ非常に少ないでしょう
what about the rice
米はどうですか
In several major rice producing countries
いくつかの主要な米生産国では
Like China, India and other countries
中国、インド、その他の国と同じように
Many countries in Southeast Asia
東南アジアの多くの国
its safe food
その安全な食べ物
By 2007, this statistic had dropped to a very low level.
2007 年までに、この統計は非常に低いレベルに低下しました。
In fact, it is still decreasing and not increasing
実際は増えずに減り続けている
so what about this problem
それで、この問題はどうですか
If some catastrophes suddenly come
突然災害が起こったら
you can't produce enough food
十分な食料を生産できない
You don't have enough food
食べ物が足りない
like deposits in our bank
私たちの銀行の預金のように
If you save less than you use
使用量よりも貯蓄量が少ない場合
Your bank balance will be gone in no time.
あなたの銀行残高はあっという間になくなってしまいます。
OK
OK
what else is there
他には何があるの
the price of oil
石油の価格
on the rise
上昇傾向に
What about the fertilizer?
肥料はどうでしょうか？
The most important thing is egg fertilizer like urea
最も重要なのは尿素などの卵肥料です
Because heavy crops must use a lot of egg fertilizer
大量の作物には卵肥料を大量に使用する必要があるため
that egg fat
その卵の脂肪
it consumes a lot of energy
多くのエネルギーを消費します
So when the price of oil goes up
それで原油価格が上がる
The price of urea will follow
尿素の価格もそれに続く
So can see it this price increase
この値上げはわかりますか
Then the price of this rice
じゃあこのお米の値段は
Of course it also rises
もちろん上がります
because you're going to use fertilizer again
また肥料を使うから
So farming needs oil
だから農業には石油が必要だ
so what about this question
それで、この質問はどうでしょうか
In fact, there is no good solution
実際のところ、良い解決策はありません
Besides these problems
こうした問題以外にも
It's even worse if you add natural disasters
自然災害も加わるとさらにひどい
Look at this Thailand in 2011
2011 年のタイを見てください。
we probably still have the impression
おそらくその印象がまだ残っているでしょう
Its whole country was flooded with a set of lake soil
その国全体が湖の土で水浸しになった
This is the point to come to this satellite
ここがこのサテライトに来るポイントです
it this country
それはこの国です
then flooded
その後浸水した
flooded this wide range
この広範囲に浸水した
Then you see even this aircraft factory is flooded
そうすれば、この航空機工場さえも浸水していることがわかります
so what year
それで何年ですか
this is 2011
これは2011年です
You can look at the international food prices
国際食品価格を確認できます
From this January to December
今年の1月から12月まで
You can see that the price of food has risen
食料品の値段が上がっているのがわかります
Of course later
もちろん後で
sometimes there is a follow up
時々フォローアップもあります
There will be food produced again
また食料が生産されるだろう
But what?
でも何？
can clearly see
はっきりと見える
As long as there is such a natural disaster
このような自然災害がある限り
It is the main food production
主要な食料生産です
The price of its food will definitely rise
食べ物の値段は確実に上がるだろう
It's not just Thailand
タイだけじゃないよ
something like this is happening
このようなことが起こっています
America in 2008
2008年のアメリカ
Major flooding in Midwest cornfields
中西部のトウモロコシ畑で大規模な洪水
this is its cornfield
ここはトウモロコシ畑です
You can't see the smoke from the corn
トウモロコシから出る煙は見えない
This is the system it irrigates
これが灌漑システムです
Of course this would cause a great loss
もちろん、そうなると大きな損失が発生します
same place
同じ場所
Last year it was sweat disaster
去年は汗の災難だった
severe sweating
ひどい発汗
large flakes of corn wheat
トウモロコシ小麦の大きなフレーク
The soybeans are all dried out like this
大豆はこんな感じで全部乾燥してます
so the same place
だから同じ場所
can have such an extreme climate
このような極端な気候が起こる可能性があります
to have a problem like this
このような問題があるとは
The entire country of the United States at that time last year
去年の当時のアメリカ全土
sweaty place
汗ばむ場所
the darker it is
暗いほど
That is, the more it dries up, the more serious it is.
つまり、乾燥すればするほど深刻になります。
its serious
それは深刻です
almost in its crop yield
収穫量はほぼそのまま
highest area
最も高いエリア
in this generation
この世代では
what was the consequence of that
その結果はどうなったのか
can be seen
見られます
last year
去年
Many newspapers often write
多くの新聞がよく書いています
The price of corn has gone up
トウモロコシの値段が上がった
Then you can see what soybeans
そうすれば、大豆が何であるかがわかります
up what 30
30まで
Will want 39% corn 52% wheat 37%
39% トウモロコシ 52% 小麦 37% が必要になります
Gold Treasury 9%
ゴールド・トレジャリー 9%
Then oil 16% and so on
次にオイル 16% など
It's just been rising. Everyone is very concerned about this issue.
増加傾向にあり、誰もがこの問題を非常に懸念しています。
Everyone goes out to eat, especially the students, it's very pitiful. I don't have much money.
みんな、特に学生が外食してるんですけど、本当に可哀想なんです、お金があまりないんです。
Eating out is getting more and more expensive
外食もどんどん高くなっていく
I experimented with cadavers eating this a few weeks ago
数週間前に死体にこれを食べさせる実験をしました
Pizza huh
ピザね
I haven't invited them for a long time
長い間彼らを招待していない
so i asked my assistant and i said
そこでアシスタントに尋ねてこう言いました
I buy all of these big Songda
私はこれらの大きなソンダをすべて購入します
say how much
いくら言う
He said more than 700 yuan, I said
彼は700元以上だと言いました、と私は言いました
I thought it was still more than 400 yuan
まだ400円以上かと思ってた
I'm sorry I haven't invited them to eat for a long time
長い間食事に誘ってなくてごめんなさい
But it's really long
でも本当に長いです
You can see that not only the United States but also Australia
アメリカだけでなくオーストラリアもそうであることがわかります。
Australia is already suffering from frequent droughts
オーストラリアはすでに頻繁な干ばつに悩まされている
Australia actually produces a lot of wheat and barley
オーストラリアは実際に小麦と大麦をたくさん生産しています
is a very important granary
非常に重要な穀倉です
It is also suffering from this drought now
今もこの干ばつに苦しんでいます
Worse is predicted by 2050
2050年までにさらに悪化すると予測されている
We all like to use 2050 as an indicator now
今では誰もが 2050 年を指標として使いたがります
How much does the population increase
人口はどれくらい増えるのか
will increase from the current 7 billion to 9 billion
現在の70億から90億に増加する
more than 9 billion
90億以上
But you can see where it's dry
でも、どこが乾いているかはわかります
This is also the darker the color, the more severe the drought
こちらも色が濃いほど干ばつが深刻であることを示します。
Many countries will have this drought
多くの国がこの干ばつに見舞われるだろう
look at this america
このアメリカを見てください
and this south america
そしてこの南アメリカ
Africa
アフリカ
Europe
ヨーロッパ
Asia
アジア
the problem of drought
干ばつの問題
is seriously global
真剣にグローバルです
Then we also have problems in Taiwan
それから台湾でも問題があります
Although we in Taiwan seem to be more redundant
台湾にいる私たちはもっと余っているように見えますが、
Even on the street, there are often some problems
路上でもトラブルはよくある
The most important thing is what problems are happening to us now
最も重要なことは、今私たちに何が起こっているのかということです
I'm sorry, how do I focus by myself?
申し訳ありませんが、自分で集中するにはどうすればよいですか?
OK Rice Cut Production
OKライスカット生産
You can see our root pruning from 1981 on this
1981年からの根の剪定の様子はこちらでご覧いただけます
So our rice crops are up to
したがって、私たちの米作物は次のとおりです
This is the statistics until 2009
これは2009年までの統計です
its cut
そのカット
cut a lot
たくさん切る
more than two and a half times
2回半以上
What about self-cultivation of food?
食の自己修養についてはどうでしょうか？
just follow up
ただフォローアップするだけ
Now the current food self-reliance is 32%
現在の食料自給率は32％
it means
その意味は
Our own Taiwan is very suitable for rice production
私たちの台湾は米の生産に非常に適しています
we produce now
私たちは今生産しています
To be able to produce the mother-in-law to rely on rice
お米に頼る義母を生み出せるように
It's probably just like this now
たぶん今もこんな感じです
about 30%
30%左右
what is the other 70%
残りの70%は何ですか
It's imported
輸入品です
imported corn wheat
輸入トウモロコシ小麦
soybeans
大豆
It has a lot of pesticides and fertilizers
農薬や肥料がたくさん入っている
and oil
そして油
that kind
そういう種類の
It all depends on foreign countries
すべては外国次第だ
Then our own food production is so little
それでは、私たち自身の食糧生産は非常にわずかです
Then there are many small farmers in Taiwan
それから、台湾には小規模農家がたくさんあります
you see most of this
これのほとんどがわかります
In fact, more than two-thirds
実際には3分の2以上が
All this one-hectare smallholders
この1ヘクタールの小規模農家はすべて
cost increases
コストが増加する
Plus we have a lot of this
さらに、これもたくさんあります
There are a lot of this luxurious farmhouse in this field
この畑にはこんな贅沢な農家がたくさんあります
luxury farmers
豪華農
Go to Nikan, Yilan after Chinese New Year
春節後は宜蘭のニカンへ
I really saw a lot of what is called a house
家というものを本当にたくさん見ました
Plant them in a kennel from the start
最初から犬小屋に植える
A lot of this, a small room, a small room in the field
たくさん、これ、小さな部屋、野原の小さな部屋
It's really a serious problem
本当に深刻な問題だよ
let's go to that america
あのアメリカへ行こう
not just America you don't look at America
アメリカだけじゃない あなたはアメリカを見ない
america is too big
アメリカは大きすぎる
then we go to what
それから何に行きますか
France United Kingdom Some countries
フランス イギリス 一部の国
Japanese Korean family
日系韓国人家族
The place where it is made is a kind of kennel
作られる場所は一種の犬小屋です
there are no pounds in it
そこにはポンドはありません
People live together in a village
人々は村で一緒に暮らしています
Only Taiwan is really a house with this
本当にこれがある家は台湾だけ
smashed together first
最初に一緒に打ち砕かれた
Is it for the high-speed rail or the Taiwan Railway?
高速鉄道用ですか、台湾鉄道用ですか？
You can see such problems
このような問題が見られます
So this will increase its production cost
そのため、生産コストが増加します
OK, let's talk again.
はい、また話しましょう。
We are now targeting this grain
私たちは今この穀物をターゲットにしています
What kind of goals do we have
私たちはどんな目標を持っていますか
Although there are many problems, we still have to do
問題はたくさんありますが、それでもやらなければなりません
first very important
まず非常に重要な
Increase production
生産量を増やす
Right, we said the population is increasing so fast
そう、人口が非常に急速に増加していると言いました
Yield is really the number one priority
収量は本当に最優先事項です
we can take a look
見てみましょう
This global statistic
この世界的な統計は、
From 74 to 2009
74 年から 2009 年まで
Around the time of the Green Revolution
緑の革命の頃
Corn, Rice, Wheat, Rapeseed
トウモロコシ、米、小麦、菜種
Both increased by 1.5 to 2.0%
ともに1.5～2.0％増加
that's all
以上
So PETA has increased a lot during this period of time
この期間にPETAは大幅に増加しました
But what?
でも何？
Many other things are also increasing in price
他にも色々なものが値上がりしてます
This is American corn
アメリカンコーンをベースにしたものです
Take this corn from IOWA as an example
アイオワ州のこのトウモロコシを例に挙げてみましょう
corn it increased by 1.6 times
トウモロコシ 1.6倍に増加
But what?
でも何？
These cost three times the machinery
これらは機械の 3 倍のコストがかかります
Four times the seed pesticide fertilizer
種子農薬肥料4倍
artificial quadruple
人工四重奏
land seven times in three years
土地三年七倍
Add up all kinds
全種類を合計すると
It costs ten times as much to produce as it produces
製造コストは生産コストの10倍
Therefore, although production increases
そのため、生産量は増えても、
But we're raising prices on everything
しかし、私たちはあらゆるものを値上げしています
So everyone needs enough food besides now
だから誰もが今以外に十分な食料を必要としている
Have enough money to buy food
食べ物を買うのに十分なお金がある
So this is a double question
これは二重の質問です
That
それか
Although it is said that in 2020
2020年と言われていますが、
In 2000, our entire period from 1960 to 2020
2000 年は、1960 年から 2020 年までの全期間を指します。
Double our production
生産量を2倍にする
But as you can see in the recent
しかし、最近の様子を見てもわかるように、
In the past 20 years, his growth rate has actually slowed down.
過去20年間で、彼の成長率は実際には鈍化しました。
This is reflected in India, Asia, China
これはインド、アジア、中国にも反映されています
His growth rate has actually slowed down.
彼の成長速度は実際には鈍化しています。
There is no way to go as fast as before
以前のように速く進む方法はありません
So to increase the yield of this crop
したがって、この作物の収量を増やすには
what are we going to do
何しようか
For a reflection
反省のために
it has to grow well
うまく成長しなければなりません
It has two very important conditions
非常に重要な条件が 2 つあります
one is environmental factors
一つは環境要因です
like sunshine, rain
太陽の光、雨のように
Another is the genetic factor
もう一つは遺伝的要因です
Environmental factors are
環境要因は、
no drought
干ばつはありません
Not too much salt, accumulation, low temperature, high temperature
塩分過多、蓄積、低温、高温
no floods etc.
洪水などはありません。
another biological way
別の生物学的方法
It means serious illness, current weight, etc.
重大な病気や現在の体重などを意味します。
These have to be prevented
これらは防止する必要があります
additional genetic factors
追加の遺伝的要因
that is how to make it
それが作り方です
Its shape is the best
形が最高です
Photosynthesis is the most efficient
光合成が最も効率が良い
The amount of encouragement it rises is the largest and the heaviest
高まる励ましの量は一番大きくて一番重い
and its roots
そしてそのルーツ
It can also absorb water and nutrients
水分や栄養も吸収できる
the effect is the best
効果は最高です
Wait, there are very, very many of these conditions
待ってください、これらの条件は非常にたくさんあります
work together to be able
できるように協力する
There is a most perfect one rice
最高に完璧な一品ご飯がある
give you the best yield
最高の収量を提供します
right
右
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
but now this
しかし今はこれ
We who did this rice research
お米の研究をした私たち
have been working hard
一生懸命働いてきた
I hope you can
私がすることができます願っています
Explore this issue from different angles
この問題をさまざまな角度から検討する
Finally these good features
最後に、これらの優れた機能
They are all concentrated in this registration.
それらはすべてこの登録に集中しています。
that probably
それはおそらく
methods of genetic engineering
遺伝子工学の手法
It may be a more important method
それはもっと重要な方法かもしれません
because in a short time
なぜなら短時間で
to achieve that
それを達成するために
In addition to production
生産以外にも
There is another very important thing to improve
改善すべきもう 1 つの非常に重要な点があります
Just look at the drought
干ばつを見てください
i just mentioned
先ほど言いました
This drought is actually a serious problem
この干ばつは実は深刻な問題です
because of you
あなたのおかげで
Very sick you always still have pesticides
とても具合が悪い、あなたはいつも農薬を持っている
But you have no rain
でも雨は降っていない
no water is no water
水がないのは水がない
It is difficult to prevent
防ぐのは難しい
It won't be easy unless I disturb artificial rain tomorrow
明日は人工雨を邪魔しない限り簡単にはいかないだろう
So this tough question
それで、この難しい質問は
It is very important for our breeding to solve
私たちの育種にとって解決することは非常に重要です
that crop
その作物
There is a big problem is
大きな問題があります
it really has a lot of water
本当に水分が多いです
daily food for each of us
私たち一人ひとりの毎日の食事
The food needed needs 3,000 liters, etc.
必要な食料は3,000リットル必要など。
Waiting for three tons of water to plant us every day
毎日3トンの水が植えられるのを待っている
the grain needed
必要な穀物
You can see 70 percent of the world's fresh water
世界の淡水の 70% を見ることができます
used on crops
作物に使用される
that this one
これは
Sorry, could it be pesticides?
すみません、農薬の可能性はありますか？
is agriculture
農業です
Most praised on agriculture
農業分野で最も高く評価された
Then industrial household water
それから工業用家庭用水
So agricultural production really uses a lot of water
農業生産では本当に大量の水を使用します
Let's be brave and don't let it
勇気を出して、そうしないようにしましょう
use so much water
水をたくさん使います
What about planting rice like this?
このまま田植えしたらどうでしょうか？
An average kilogram of rice
米の平均キログラム
It also uses 2.5 tons
2.5トンも使います
2500 liters of this water
この水2500リットル
the world probably
おそらく世界
nearly one-third of the water
水の約3分の1
It is used for rice irrigation
水田の灌漑に使われています
that other rice
他のご飯
In addition to the evaporation of water from the leaves
葉からの水分の蒸発に加えて、
The largest part is the surface of the water
一番大きい部分は水面です
Surface water in the field
畑の地表水
just evaporate
ただ蒸発するだけ
Of course some of it will seep a little below the ground.
もちろん、その一部は地下に浸透していきます。
But its evaporation from the surface is a serious problem
しかし、表面からの蒸発は深刻な問題です
So can we use less water to grow rice?
では、水の使用量を減らして米を栽培することはできるのでしょうか？
Can you stop soaking in water all the time?
ずっと水に浸かるのをやめられますか？
Of course we just mentioned that
もちろん、先ほども言いましたが、
Yes weed control is an important reason
はい、雑草対策は重要な理由です
But in fact, there are many heavier methods
しかし実際には、もっと重いメソッドがたくさんあります
can actually assist in reducing this weed problem
実際にこの雑草問題を減らすのに役立ちます
The water in Taiwan is the same
台湾の水も同じ
That's about three quarters of water
それは水の約4分の3です
used in this agriculture
この農業で使われている
But we also often have this problem of water shortage.
しかし、水不足の問題もしばしば発生します。
Sometimes when there is a lack of water
時々水が不足するときがあります
like the recent south central
像最近中南部
Although it rains a lot in Taipei
台北は雨が多いですが、
During the Chinese New Year, everyone is very happy to go to South Central
中国の旧正月には、みんなとても喜んでサウスセントラルに行きます
The weather is very good in the south-central
中南部はとても良い天気です
Probably Taipei is very boring, the teacher is raining
おそらく台北はとても退屈です、先生は雨が降っています
But people in Taipei are actually lucky
でも台北の人たちは実は幸運なんです
Because there is almost no shortage of water in Taipei
台北では水不足がほとんどないので、
Our Bandit Reservoir has always been difficult
私たちの山賊貯水池は常に困難でした
However, the central and southern regions are often in this period of winter
ただし、中南部ではこの時期は冬になることが多いです。
go really short of water
本当に水が不足する
Because there is no typhoon
台風がないので
So if it's too severe
それであまりにもひどい場合は
Farmers don't plant rice after spring
農家は春以降は田植えをしない
The government began to say that there is a shortage of water
政府は水が不足していると言い始めた
We are going to use water in industry
産業で水を使用する予定です
Farmers don't farm
農家は農業をしない
So this is actually a regular
ということで、実はこれが定番なんです
It must happen every few years
それは数年ごとに起こるはずです
Then the peasants are poor
そうなると農民は貧乏になる
often forget the state of mind
精神状態を忘れることが多い
For farmers, although the government subsidizes
農家にとっては、政府は補助金を出しますが、
hardworking farmer
勤勉な農民
he doesn't like watching this too much
彼はこれを見るのがあまり好きではありません
Change this field back home
このフィールドをホームに変更します
over there
そちら側
OK, except that Taiwan has such a problem
OK、台湾がそのような問題を抱えていることを除けば
Africa is also a serious problem
アフリカも深刻な問題
Africa also grows a lot of corn
アフリカではトウモロコシもたくさん栽培されています
is their main food
彼らの主食です
But this corn is also very sensitive to dry welding
しかし、このトウモロコシは乾式溶接にも非常に弱いです
The darker the country
国が暗いほど
It means that it can have an irrigation system
それは灌漑システムを備えていることができることを意味します
is more sufficient
もっと十分です
Are these colors faded?
これらの色は色あせていますか？
It is a place that lacks water
水の少ない場所です
So water scarcity is a serious problem in Africa
アフリカでは水不足が深刻な問題となっている
by 2020
2020年までに
predicted to be more serious
より深刻になると予想される
and may
そしてかもしれない
Corn production will be reduced by 50%
トウモロコシの生産量は50％削減される
what to do
何をすべきか
Its population growth is also one of the fastest in the region
人口増加もこの地域で最も速い国の一つです
outside of asia
アジアの外
Then cut it in half
それから半分に切ります
OK, except what we just said
OK、今言ったこと以外は
The purpose of forecasting is to increase production
予測の目的は生産量を増やすことです
and sweat resistant
汗に強い
In fact, we also hope to improve crops
実際、私たちは作物の改良も望んでいます。
Can you make this food more nutritious?
この食べ物をもっと栄養価の高いものにしてもらえますか?
can be good for our health
私たちの健康に良いかもしれない
So this in our research
私たちの調査ではこれが
Or many people have done a lot in other research
あるいは、多くの人が他の研究で多くのことを行っています
Then let's take an example
それでは例を挙げてみましょう
Our genetic engineering is to increase the nutrition of food
私たちの遺伝子工学は食物の栄養を増やすことです
what can be done
何ができるか
That's beta carotene
それがベータカロテンです
that is to say let this one
つまり、これをしましょう
Hope to be able to predict that crop?
その作物を予測できるといいですね?
It contains beta carotene
βカロテンが含まれているので
because most crops
なぜなら、ほとんどの作物は
Amount of Beta Carotene Contained
βカロテン含有量
Too much is not enough
多すぎると十分ではありません
that this is the world
これが世界だということ
caused by vitamin A deficiency
ビタミンA欠乏症によって引き起こされる
This night mango shrimp eye
この夜はマンゴーシュリンプアイ
Shrimp eyes are vitamin A deficiency
エビの目はビタミンA欠乏症
is a major reason
大きな理由です
The green one is fine.
緑色のものは大丈夫です。
in this brain
この脳内で
Can get enough vitamin A or betavenous waves
十分なビタミンAまたはベタ静脈波を得ることができます
But these countries
しかしこれらの国は
what about the yellow
黄色はどうですか
The yellow one is already common
黄色はもう一般的ですね
that red one is very bad
あの赤いのはとても悪いです
so what
だから何
There are many countries in this
この中にはたくさんの国がある
Actually more or less
実際には多かれ少なかれ
will have some of this
これの一部を持っているでしょう
vitamin deficiency problem
ビタミン欠乏の問題
Many pregnant women are also deficient in vitamin A
多くの妊婦もビタミンA欠乏症です
Then this miscarriage
そして今回の流産
Then the kid talks nonsense
それから子供はナンセンスを話します
then many die
それから多くの人が死ぬ
so in this
それでこれで
beta carrot tree
ベータニンジンの木
he is
彼は
What about the topic we want to talk about?
私たちが話したいテーマについてはどうですか？
He put it in this rice
彼はそれをこのご飯に入れました
that's because he turned golden
それは彼が黄金色になったからです
We know that beta carrot trees are yellow
ベータニンジンの木は黄色であることは知っています
so when yellow
だから黄色のときは
he called me golden rice
彼は私をゴールデンライスと呼んだ
What about the rice?
米はどうですか
Inside he has a right of this beta carrot tree
彼は内部でこのベータニンジンの木の権利を持っています
meaning that if it can go through some process
つまり、何らかのプロセスを経ることができれば、
some genes exist
いくつかの遺伝子が存在する
through a process
プロセスを通じて
beta carotene
ベータカロチン
But rice itself does not have these enzymes
しかし、お米自体にはこれらの酵素はありません
So it has the original precursor empty
したがって、元のプリカーサーは空です
But there is no way to convert it into beta carotene
しかし、それをベータカロチンに変換する方法はありません
beta carotene
ベータカロチン
If we eat in the body
体内で食べると
it can be converted into vitamin A
ビタミンAに変換できる
So this scientist
それでこの科学者は
Humane
人道的
He hoped that the rice could be produced
彼は米が生産できることを望んでいた
Because rice is actually the staple food of 50% of the population
米は実際に人口の50％の主食だから
Especially many people in this relatively weak or region
特にこの比較的弱い地域に多くの人が住んでいます
Eat rice as the staple food
お米を主食として食べる
If you can let him eat the rice
彼にご飯を食べさせてもらえたら
There is this vitamin beta carrot
こんなビタミンβニンジンがあります
If the plain skin is converted into beta life A
素肌がベータライフAに変身したら
Many of the problems we just mentioned can be solved
先ほど述べた問題の多くは解決可能です
So this technique was published in Science in 2000
この技術は 2000 年に Science 誌に掲載されました。
is a very sensational one thing
それはとてもセンセーショナルな事だ
Because it's the first time to do this in a plant
工場でこんなことするのは初めてなので
Genetic engineering alters its metabolic pathways
遺伝子工学により代謝経路が変化する
Make it possible to generate this Beta Robb tree
この Beta Robb ツリーを生成できるようにする
Later this technique was also used in other vegetables
その後、この技術は他の野菜にも使用されました
corn top
コーントップ
The corn used to look yellow
トウモロコシは黄色く見えていました
Actually it's not a Beta Robin tree
実はこれはベータロビンの木ではありません
So they put it in this corn too
それで彼らはこのトウモロコシにもそれを入れました
Then come to predict this breed Mr.
それから、この品種を予測するようになります、ミスター。
this is the gentleman
これが紳士です
The Ingeborg Park in Sweden
スウェーデンのインゲボルグ公園
that's his collaborator
それは彼の協力者です
Peter Bayer
ピーター・バイヤー
He published this report in 2000
彼はこの報告書を 2000 年に発表しました
The day I just talked about Science
ちょうど科学について話した日
very sensational
とてもセンセーショナルな
But at that time a two-year-old child
でもその時は2歳の子供が
To eat three kilograms of golden rice
ゴールデンライスを3キロ食べるには
To be able to get enough Beta Robb trees
十分な数のベータ ロブ ツリーを入手できるようにするため
So this environmental protection group keeps canceling him.
そのため、この環境保護団体は彼をキャンセルし続けています。
So it's useless to you
だからあなたには役に立たない
How is it possible that a child only weighs three kilograms a day
子どもの体重が1日に3キロしか減らないなんて、どうしてあり得るのでしょう？
that's all eaten up
それはすべて食べられました
Can't get enough of this beta robin tree
このベータ ロビン ツリーがたまりません
so wait he waited 10 years
だから待って、彼は10年待った
Around 2001 he retired
2001年頃に引退
Golden Girl still has no way to promote
ゴールデンガールはまだプロモーションする方法がない
But in the process he kept improving
しかしその過程で彼は改善を続けた
In 2005
2005年
72 grams children eat 72 grams per day
72グラムの子供たちは1日に72グラムを食べる
Just a small handful and a small bowl
ほんの一握りと小さなボウルだけ
will be able to get enough of the golden girl
黄金の少女を十分に得ることができるでしょう
He's retired
彼は退職しました
Now only his collaborator Peter Bayer
現在、彼の協力者はピーター・バイエルのみとなっている
continue his efforts
彼の努力を続ける
In this Philippine International Year of Rice is the center
今年のフィリピン国際米年は中心です
They are now constantly promoting this technology
彼らは現在、このテクノロジーを継続的に宣伝しています
Because different regions of the world
世界のさまざまな地域があるため、
Different countries
さまざまな国
The rice varieties he grows are different
彼が栽培する米の品種は異なります
So he wants to put this gene on different breeds
そこで彼はこの遺伝子をさまざまな品種に導入したいと考えています
So in the future, different countries can grow
したがって、将来的にはさまざまな国が成長する可能性があります
I have always hoped that it can be commercialized as soon as possible.
一日も早い商品化をずっと願っております。
Because it is really possible every year
本当に毎年そうなるから
very, very much of this life
この人生のとてもとても
But environmental groups continue to protest
しかし環境団体は抗議活動を続けている
What about the research and development of this golden rice?
このゴールデンライスの研究開発はどうなっているのでしょうか？
Probably only cost about two million dollars
たぶん200万くらいしかかからない
But in order to cope with environmental groups doing biosafety assessments
しかし、生物学的安全性評価を行っている環境団体に対処するために
$20 million spent
2000万ドルを費やした
There is still no way to promote
未だに宣伝方法が無い
Many people are impatient
多くの人はせっかちです
so this one this one is the most recent
それで、これはこれが最新のものです
Sorry I forgot to call this
ごめんなさい、こちらに電話するのを忘れてしまいました
Where did it come from?
それはどこから来たのか？
This is Nature
これが自然です
An article published by Nature
Nature に掲載された記事
it's talking about this
それはこのことについて話している
Chinese children's golden rice experiment
中国の子供たちのゴールデンライス実験
and then punished
そして罰せられた
This is why some scientists were punished
これが一部の科学者が処罰された理由です
This is a one in Boston
これはボストンにあるものです
Cup University of Boston, USA
カップ アメリカ、ボストン大学
Tang Guanwen, a female professor of Chinese descent
唐冠文さんは中国系の女性教授。
Then she and Xinjiang
それから彼女と新疆
Collaboration with some scholars in Xinjiang, Mainland China
中国本土の新疆ウイグル自治区の学者との共同研究
Come
来て
Eat this gold and silver for little ones
小さな子供たちにこの金と銀を食べさせてください
Then I read his articles here
それから私はここで彼の記事を読みました
The two sides are talking about each other
双方がお互いについて話し合っています
the scientists he said
彼が言った科学者たちは
He also passed through many units
彼はまた多くのユニットを通過しました
I agreed to do this experiment.
私はこの実験を行うことに同意しました。
But after this matter was exposed by the media
しかしこの件がマスコミに暴露されてからは
Many people are afraid
多くの人が恐れています
then start by saying
それからこう言って始めます
We were originally publishing the report
私たちは当初レポートを発行していました
the people who hang on to you start saying
あなたにしがみついている人たちはこう言い始めます
We also don't know what experiments he was doing.
彼がどのような実験を行っていたのかも分かりません。
then i have nothing to do with me
それなら私とは何の関係もありません
Because in the end someone was arrested and locked up
結局誰かが逮捕されて監禁されたから
so it's a pity
だから残念だ
Then he drew this cartoon
それから彼はこの漫画を描きました
like an american
アメリカ人のように
because you see he has an american flag on his tie
なぜなら彼のネクタイにはアメリカの国旗が付いているのが見えるからです
Then he put this gold and silver this gold and silver
それから彼はこの金と銀を置きました
for the children of China
中国の子供たちのために
So in fact his report
実際、彼のレポートは
published has been published
公開されました 公開されました
And his result is very good
そして彼の結果はとても良いです
Because they had three sets of experiments
彼らは 3 セットの実験を行ったので、
A group is to eat gold
グループは金を食べることです
One group is to eat spinach
1つのグループはほうれん草を食べます
Another group is to eat
別のグループは食事をする予定です
Beta Carotene Capsules
ベータカロテンカプセル
The results of it
その結果
Eating gold gives you exactly the same effect as taking beta carotene capsules
金を食べるとベータカロテンカプセルを摂取するのと全く同じ効果が得られます
So it actually works really well
それで実際にはとてもうまく機能します
But because of the media
でもメディアのせいで
Then the protests of environmental groups
その後、環境団体の抗議活動が
Now temporarily suppressed again
現在は再び一時的に抑制されています
But the mainland
でも本土は
He's genetically engineered various crops
彼はさまざまな作物を遺伝子組み換えした
A very positive country
とてもポジティブな国
All but the most active countries in the world
世界で最も活動的な国を除くすべての国
The United States is of course very active
もちろんアメリカも非常に積極的です
or countries in the Americas
またはアメリカ大陸の国々
Because they make a lot of money by exporting this gene
彼らはこの遺伝子を輸出することで大儲けしているからです
The other one is like China, India
もう一つは中国、インドのようなものです
because he has too many people
彼には人が多すぎるから
He is very sensitive to the food of the people
彼は人の食べ物にとても敏感です
Our government in Taiwan is not sensitive at all
私たちの台湾政府はまったく敏感ではありません
we must be
私たちはそうでなければなりません
Autonomy is only 32%
自律性はわずか 32%
Do you know what percentage is in mainland China?
中国本土が何パーセントか知っていますか？
it's 95%
95%です
So mainland China pays more attention to whether its people can have enough to eat
そのため、中国本土は国民が十分な食料を確保できるかどうかにより注意を払っている
You can't have enough to eat, you can't eat enough
十分に食べられない、十分に食べられない
If you can't eat enough, you will be messed up
十分に食べないと体がおかしくなるよ
So the top executives in the mainland said
そこで本土の高級幹部らはこう言った。
Although this happened
こんな事があったのに
Our genetic engineering technology is still the same
遺伝子組み換え技術は今も変わらない
Because they see the future really depends on this technology
なぜなら、彼らは未来が本当にこのテクノロジーに依存していると考えているからです。
So in addition to the golden rice just mentioned
先ほどのゴールデンライスに加えて
In fact, there are many other things to do
実は他にもやるべきことがたくさんあるのですが、
many people are doing
多くの人がやっています
increase its protein content
タンパク質含有量を増やす
Iron core, anti-oxidant, etc.
鉄芯、酸化防止剤など
Actually m it is very
実はとてもそうなんです
Its protein quality is very good
たんぱく質の質がとても良い
easy to digest
消化しやすい
Too bad it's not high enough
残念ながら高さが足りない
So many people say
とても多くの人が言います
can hope to increase its protein content
タンパク質含有量の増加が期待できます
These genetically engineered plants
これらの遺伝子組み換え植物は、
what else can be done
他に何ができるか
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
it can produce this oral vaccine
この経口ワクチンを製造できる
That is to say, you are produced in the tomato
つまり、あなたはトマトから作られます。
produced in spinach
ほうれん草で作られる
You just dry the capsules and put them on
カプセルを乾燥させて装着するだけです
Then the doctor will tell you
そしたらお医者さんが教えてくれますよ
you eat two this week
今週は2つ食べますか
next week two
来週2週目
Eat a few in a few weeks
数週間に数個食べる
you are vaccinated
あなたは予防接種を受けています
For many countries in this weak or region
この弱い地域の多くの国にとって
is very important
はとても重要です
Because many vaccines need to be iced
多くのワクチンは氷で冷やす必要があるため
They don't have a fridge, they don't have mats
冷蔵庫もないし、マットもない
or no medical staff
もしくは医療スタッフがいない
Can help them inoculate these diseases
これらの病気の予防接種に役立ちます
So this oral vaccine
それでこの経口ワクチンは
actually very good
実際にとても良い
i think kids
子供たちだと思います
not only children
子どもたちだけではなく
Many adults are afraid of needles
針を怖がる大人は多い
so in the future
だから将来的には
this oral vaccine
この経口ワクチン
You just eat it and get vaccinated.
それを食べて予防接種を受けるだけです。
This is a lot of successful examples
成功例がたくさんあります
has been very successful
とても成功しました
And some of them are already commercialized
そのうちのいくつかはすでに商品化されています
so this
したがって、この
It was drawn by my daughter
娘が描いたものです
Then he draws his brother
それから彼は弟を描きます
well , this time he drew his dad
さて、今回はお父さんを描きました
Head of education teacher
教育長老師
that because we all know
それは私たち全員が知っているからです
It's just that people don't like injections.
ただ、人々は注射が嫌いです。
But this future oral vaccine
しかし、この将来の経口ワクチンは
is really able to do this
本当にこれができる
ok , ok , let ' s talk again
わかりました、わかりました、また話しましょう
What kind of work are we doing in Taiwan
私たちは台湾でどのような仕事をしていますか
We are doing the function letter gold of the plant
植物の機能文字金をやってます
Somatic research, it should be said that the functional information of rice
イネの機能情報ともいえる体性研究
body research
体の研究
Because we need to borrow useful genes from plants
植物から有用な遺伝子を借用する必要があるため
we just talked a lot
私たちはただたくさん話しました
Can do this kind of genetic engineering law
こんな遺伝子組み換え法ができるんだ
then we have to find out
それから私たちは調べなければなりません
what kind of genes are useful
どのような遺伝子が役に立つのか
Then let's put the usage where I want it
それでは、必要な場所に使用法を配置しましょう
Then this is his rice
じゃあこれが彼のご飯です
A schematic diagram of the 12 chromosomes
12本の染色体の模式図
He refers to the number of his genes one by one
彼は自分の遺伝子の数を一つ一つ言及する
The darker the color, the number of genes
色が濃いほど遺伝子の数が多い
more
もっと
Then this in Japanese
じゃあ日本語でこれ
when they first started
彼らが最初に始めたとき
It is he who does the job of interpreting
通訳の仕事をしているのは彼です
What is an explanation?
説明とは何ですか?
as if
かのように
word in a dictionary
辞書の単語
ABCD is in a mess
ABCDは混乱しています
Then what
じゃあ何
You're going to start arranging it in ABCD
ABCDで並べ始めます
Then XYZ lines up
次にXYZが並びます
So it's a job of interpretation
だからそれは解釈の仕事だよ
So the position of each experience on the chromosome
したがって、染色体上のそれぞれの経験の位置は
you fix it
あなたがそれを修正します
that job is very important
その仕事はとても重要です
so at first
だから最初は
japanese do it themselves
日本人は自分たちでやる
when he started doing
彼がやり始めたとき
Many people laugh at him as stupid
多くの人は彼を愚かだと笑います
Because this job costs a lot of money
この仕事には多額のお金がかかるので、
it will take a lot of time
とても時間がかかります
that was later
それは後のことだった
Many countries have begun to discover
多くの国が発見し始めています
This is a very important job
これはとても重要な仕事です
then start assisting
それから支援を始めます
turn around and look at him
振り返って彼を見てください
have completed this chromosome
この染色体が完成しました
the work of interpretation
解釈の仕事
National conditions can be hung on it
国家条件をそれに掛けることができる
good
良い
So Japan hangs this much
つまり日本はこれほどまでにハングアップしているのだ
then other countries
それから他の国
Then our national flag of the Republic of China
それから中華民国の国旗
This is us in 1999 2004
これは 1999 年 2004 年の私たちです
former botanical institute
元植物研究所
It is now called Plant Language Living Documentation Office
現在は「Plant Language Living Documentation Office」と呼ばれています。
This is a lot of teachers
こんなにたくさんの先生がいるのに
Including Mr. Xi Yu as the program host
Xi Yu氏を番組司会者に迎えて
he is here now
彼は今ここにいます
we gritted our teeth
私たちは歯を食いしばった
Because it costs a lot of money to do it
やるにはかなりのお金がかかるので、
that just started
それは始まったばかりです
I also want to say if it's me
私だったら言いたい
don't totally do that much
全然そんなことしないで
don't spend so much money
そんなにお金を使わないでください
But our neighbors are not alone
しかし、私たちの隣人は一人ではありません
After that, the national flag will be placed with us
その後、国旗は私たちと一緒に置かれます
So we did it by ourselves
だから自分たちでやりました
so what about our flag
それで、私たちの旗はどうですか
always on the fifth chromosome
常に5番目の染色体上にある
No one can remove him
誰も彼を取り除くことはできない
So this is a very important job
ですから、これはとても重要な仕事です
Alright, let's line up from ABCD to XYZ
よし、ABCDからXYZまで並びましょう
But the problem is he didn't hold tight
しかし問題は彼がしっかりと抱きつかなかったことだ
you don't know what it means to say book
本って言うのが何を意味するのか分からない
what does girl mean
女の子ってどういう意味ですか
Then we have to give him meaning
それから私たちは彼に意味を与えなければなりません
So we go down and take each
それで私たちは降りてそれぞれを取ります
The function of the gene needs to be solved
遺伝子の機能を解明する必要がある
Waterways contain nearly 40,000 genes
水路には約 40,000 個の遺伝子が含まれている
How to study the functions of so many genes
非常に多くの遺伝子の機能を研究する方法
it's difficult
それは難しい
Because often a person's life
なぜなら、多くの場合、人の人生は
Studying only one gene previously
以前に 1 つの遺伝子だけを研究した
In other words, several people are studying a single gene
言い換えれば、複数の人が単一の遺伝子を研究しているということです
So we have a strategy
そこで私たちには戦略があります
That is to say, we just use the method of genetic engineering
つまり、遺伝子工学の手法を使っているだけです。
Insert it from a foreign gene
外来遺伝子から挿入する
Feel free to plug in and have a chance
気軽にプラグインしてチャンスを掴んでください
it plugs into the gene
それは遺伝子に組み込まれます
It will destroy the gene
遺伝子を破壊することになる
what happens to it after it is destroyed
破壊された後はどうなるのか
mutation
突然変異
Let's talk about mutations later
突然変異については後で話しましょう
So here we are
それで、ここにいます
I didn't write here
ここには書いてないけど
Ten years from roughly 2002 to 2012
およそ2002年から2012年までの10年間
Doing this job for more than ten years
この仕事を10年以上続けている
Then we build this channel
次に、このチャンネルを構築します
Gene Mutation Database and Database
遺伝子変異データベースとデータベース
In total we have more than 100,000 mutant lines
合計で 100,000 を超える変異株が存在します
Then what gene, what DNA is inserted into our
では、私たちの体内にはどのような遺伝子、どのようなDNAが挿入されているのでしょうか？
we all have to figure it out
私たち全員がそれを理解する必要があります
Make a database with more than 60,000
60,000件以上のデータベースを構築
So we publish this report
そこでこのレポートを公開します
Mr. Li and other cooperating teachers
李先生と他の協力教員
This is a very important job
これはとても重要な仕事です
Because all over the world like this
世界中がこんな感じだから
Mutation library and database like this
変異ライブラリとデータベースはこんな感じ
also only 4
それも4つだけ
Taiwan, South Korea, China and France
台湾、韓国、中国、フランス
China, of course, has many
もちろん中国にもたくさんある
Because it has a lot of people, it has to do this thing
人が多いからこういうことをしなければならない
it is also very easy to do
それもとても簡単です
But in terms of quality and publicity
しかし、品質と宣伝の点で
On the ease of use of the database
データベースの使いやすさについて
Taiwan and South Korea are the two best general pools
一般プールでは台湾と韓国がトップ2
Then we added some special new clothes
それから特別な新しい服を追加しました
I have time to explain to you
あなたに説明する時間があります
That is to say, our quality is actually quite good.
つまり、当社の品質は実際には非常に優れています
So we accumulated like this
こうやって積み上げていきました
Picture total circle library
絵トータルサークルライブラリー
Then we published
それから私たちは出版しました
One year later there will be this Science
1年後にはこの科学が生まれるだろう
sorry for the question
質問して申し訳ありません
Cannot return the ticket directly
チケットを直接返却することはできません
Puncture Science
穿刺科学
He just came one day to give my aunt
ある日、彼は突然叔母のところにやって来ました。
in 2008
2008年に
I published in 2007
2007年に出版しました
he just told us
彼はちょうど私たちに言いました
tell me
教えて
Our report
私たちのレポート
In the plant field of the world
世界の植物畑で
The number of times used by the camp is the top one percent
キャンプの利用回数は上位1パーセント
So it's a big honor
とても光栄なことです
So he asked me a lot of questions
そこで彼は私にたくさんの質問をしました
say why
理由を言ってごらん
Your total library
あなたのライブラリ全体
Can be used by so many people
たくさんの人に使ってもらえる
I will tell them the reason
彼らに理由を話します
I said that everyone paid attention
みんな注目してるって言ってた
Our total library
私たちの総合ライブラリ
and why
なぜ
This was just introduced by the vice president
これは副社長から紹介されたばかりです
Our Gates Foundation
私たちのゲイツ財団
support us to do
私たちが行うことをサポートしてください
This project of a western rice in this world
この世界の洋米プロジェクト
Because rice is a three-type plant
お米は三種類の植物だから
That's like corn sorghum
トウモロコシソルガムみたいなもんだな
Sugarcane is a four-type plant
サトウキビは4つのタイプの植物です
Its photosynthesis efficiency is better
光合成効率が良い
well, we don't have time to explain this today
さて、今日はこれを説明する時間がありません
But now everyone wants to say
でも今、誰もが言いたいのは
Can convert rice into something like corn sorghum
米をコーンソルガムのようなものに変えることができる
Its efficiency of photosynthesis is improved
光合成の効率が向上します
In this way, its yield can be increased
このようにして、収量を増やすことができます
Because the photosynthetic efficiency of corn is 40% higher than that of rice
トウモロコシの光合成効率はイネの40％も高いため
He said that if the photosynthetic efficiency of rice can
イネの光合成効率が向上すれば、
If it is increased by 140% like corn
トウモロコシのように140%に増えたら
We could probably be more than 40 percent of the population
人口の40パーセントを増やすことができるかもしれない
So that's why it's important to have a global program
だからこそ、グローバルなプログラムを持つことが重要です
There are nearly 25 research laboratories around the world participating
世界中の約 25 の研究機関が参加しています
Then Mr. Li Yu and I represent Taiwan
それから、李宇さんと私は台湾代表です。
It's in this plan
このプランの中にあります
So this also shows that our
したがって、これはまた、私たちの
An importance of the general research library
総合研究図書館の重要性
Okay, so what is a mutation?
さて、突然変異とは何ですか？
What exactly is our general research library doing?
私たちの総合研究図書館は具体的に何をしているのでしょうか?
This is a diagram
これは概略図です
That is to say, the nucleus inside our cells
つまり、私たちの細胞の中の核です。
It contains our chromosomes
そこには私たちの染色体が含まれています
Chromosomes have DNA
染色体にはDNAがある
it's our genetics
それは私たちの遺伝子です
genetic material
遺伝物質
Then our DNA will make protein
そして私たちのDNAはタンパク質を作ります
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
We just insert the DNA from the outside
DNAを外側から挿入するだけです
right to destroy the gene
遺伝子を破壊する権利
So it's us inserting the gene
つまり、遺伝子を挿入するのは私たちです
So something like this
それで、このようなもの
Your protein is also destroyed
タンパク質も破壊される
Then it starts to have some traits
その後、いくつかの特徴が現れ始めます
Normally, there is only one flower
通常、花は1つだけです
I am now three flowers
私は今、三輪の花です
This seed was originally so small, but it has become so big
この種はもともと小さかったのですが、こんなに大きくなりました
Originally without color, it becomes colored
元々色が無いのに色が付く
I used to be so tall, but now I'm so short
昔はとても背が高かったのに、今はとても背が低くなりました
I used to be so tall, I became so tall
あんなに背が高かったのに、こんなに背が高くなった
higher
より高い
This can grow to over 200 cm in a greenhouse
温室では200cm以上に成長することもあります
This should have gone up
これは上がるはずだった
It loses its direction and keeps spinning
方向を失って回り続ける
and this angle
そしてこの角度
should have been upwards
上向きだったはず
it becomes horizontal
水平になります
the leaves swell
葉が膨らむ
Then some leafy trees are gone
その後、いくつかの葉の茂った木がなくなりました
There are so many
たくさんあります
we are a vault
私たちは保管庫です
There are a lot of such univariate traits in it.
そのような一変量の形質がたくさんあります。
allows us to study many gene functions
多くの遺伝子機能を研究できるようになります
because i know now
私は今知っているので
what kind of genetic disruption is this one
これはどのような遺伝子破壊ですか
Then let me become like this
じゃあこうなってみよう
This is a method for studying gene function
遺伝子の機能を研究する方法です
Then we get from our general research database
次に、一般的な研究データベースから取得します。
just find some important genes
いくつかの重要な遺伝子を見つけてください
This is the meter that controls it
これがそれを制御するメーターです
That can also be high yield
それは高収量にもなり得る
You can see the meter get bigger
メーターが大きくなっているのがわかります
Broken and more
壊れたものなど
the whole encouragement
全体の励まし
it also increases
それも増えます
Then this is cooperating with foreign biotechnology companies
それから、これは海外のバイオテクノロジー企業と協力しています
this effect
この効果
they work pretty well
彼らはかなりうまく機能します
what about the other
もう一方はどうですか
We just mentioned the first green revolution
先ほど第一次緑の革命について触れました
This rice and wheat make it dwarf
この米と麦は矮小化する
right
右
so we are
だから私たちは
But now the traditional filter
しかし今では従来のフィルターが
It's not easy for you to control its height at will
高さを自由にコントロールするのは簡単ではありません
The current rice is still somewhat too high
今の米はまだちょっと高すぎる
If possible in such
できればそんな中で
Almost 80% of the words left
ほぼ80％の単語が残っています
or 70% its that height might be just right
もしくは70%くらいの高さがちょうどいいかもしれない
So now we can filter out varieties like this
これで、このような品種をフィルタリングできるようになりました
so any height is fine
だから高さは何でもいいよ
Then let's look at its output
次に、その出力を見てみましょう
Sure enough, this height
やっぱりこの高さ
Its output can be increased by 30%
出力は30%増加可能
And it is also more resistant to soldering
また、はんだ付けに対する耐性も向上しています
So this is what we have now
これが今私たちが持っているものです
Some research results that can be done in Taiwan
台湾でできる研究成果の一部
And we just mentioned that
そして先ほども言いましたが、
Is this a dry soldering problem?
これは乾式はんだ付けの問題でしょうか？
we also have this gene
私たちにもこの遺伝子があります
What about gene transfer?
遺伝子導入についてはどうですか？
experience non-experience you from appearance
外見からあなたを経験しない
Can't see it
見えない
But you didn't water for two weeks
でも2週間も水をあげていない
The leaves are curled up
葉が丸まっています
Then you water it for another thirty minutes
それからさらに30分間水やりをします
Only genetically engineered it can recover
遺伝子組み換えでのみ回復できる
To genetically engineered it dies
遺伝子組み換えすると死ぬ
good
良い
In such a dry place in the future
こんな乾いた未来の場所で
Is it possible that we can grow some rice
お米を作ることはできるでしょうか？
good
良い
This is a dream to pursue
これは追い求める夢です
this is
これは
This is Ang Lee, he also said
こちらはアン・リー、彼もこう言いました
he has been chasing his dream
彼は夢を追ってきた
Then he also succeeded
その後、彼も成功しました
I think for those of us who do molecular biology
分子生物学をやっている私たちにとっては
We also often have a dream
私たちもよく夢を見ます
It's actually based on your imagination
それは実際にはあなたの想像に基づいています
There are many things that are possible in the future
将来的には可能性のあることがたくさんあります
Then the first question is actually a lot of questions
最初の質問は実際にはたくさんの質問です
That is, in many countries, the temperature may be too low
つまり、多くの国では気温が低すぎる可能性があります
Or high dimension and high altitude or something
それとも高次元とか高地とか
Sometimes it's cold in winter
冬は寒いこともあります
Many crops will freeze to death
多くの作物が凍って枯れてしまうだろう
Therefore, the first question is also an important issue.
したがって、最初の質問も重要な問題です。
We have a waterway of genetically modified genes here
ここには遺伝子組み換え遺伝子の水路がある
This is a non-genetic diversion
これは非遺伝的転用です
This one here is also a gene
これも遺伝子です
It's just that we genetically make it behave less
ただ私たちが遺伝的に行動を鈍くさせているだけです
so it won't work
だからそれはうまくいきません
It won't work after seven or eight hours on the fourth road
4本目の道路で7時間か8時間経っても機能しません
Then this non-gene and this have a lot of performance
じゃあ、この非遺伝子とこれはかなりのパフォーマンスを持っています
The genes we gave it were okay
私たちが与えた遺伝子は大丈夫だった
That's 18 hours later
それは18時間後です
Only the water height of our genes can survive
私たちの遺伝子の水の高さだけが生き残ることができます
The non-genetic ones and the ones that we make the gene expression less will not work
非遺伝子のものや遺伝子発現を低くしたものは機能しません
So this is the cold resistance gene
これが耐寒性遺伝子です
so many places are too cold
とても多くの場所が寒すぎる
Can we also be in those places in the future
将来私たちもあの場所に行けるだろうか
These cold resistance genes can also be planted
これらの耐寒性遺伝子も植えることができます
now because it is
今だから
really urgent
本当に緊急です
Many places were originally unsuitable for planting crops
もともと作物を植えるのに適さない場所が多かった
We will all find ways to plant
みんなで植える方法を見つけよう
what about words
言葉はどうですか
Originally also
もともとも
We have this genetically modified waterway
私たちはこの遺伝子組み換えされた水路を持っています
before processing
加工前
This is
これは
Also upgrade the fly gene
ハエの遺伝子もアップグレードする
The five next to this
この隣の5つ
All five lines were genetically transformed
5つの系統すべてが遺伝子形質転換された
then soak in salt water
その後塩水に浸します
250g minimum
最低250g
it's very high in salt
塩分がとても高いです
salt concentration
塩分濃度
almost like sea water
ほぼ海水のよう
This soaked for three weeks
これを3週間漬け込みました
You see, this genetically transformed person is dead
ほら、遺伝子組み換えされたこの人は死んでる
What we genetically transform can also be peeled off
遺伝子組み換えしたものも剥がせる
So this gene is very powerful
この遺伝子は非常に強力です
our this
私たちのこれ
This Taiwan, this southwest salt
この台湾、この西南の塩
There are still many deserted salt pans
寂れた塩田がまだたくさんある
What about the future?
将来についてはどうですか？
Now
現在
Is it possible in the future
将来的には可能ですか
These crops can also be grown
こんな作物も栽培できます
good ok
いいよ、わかった
ok finally let's talk about this
さて、最後にこれについて話しましょう
Current Global Trends in GM Crops
GM作物の現在の世界的傾向
Because we've talked so much about genetics
遺伝についてたくさん話したので
that global
そのグローバルな
everybody every country
どこの国でもみんな
what kind of thought is it now
今はどんな考えですか
what are they doing
彼らは何をしていますか
this
これ
Genetic crops started in 1996
1996年に始まった遺伝子作物
So this curve you can see
この曲線はご覧のとおりです
by 2011
2011年までに
His increased area
彼の増加した領域
This is a developing country
ここは発展途上国です
combined by developing countries
発展途上国を合わせたもの
only so much time
ほんの少しの時間だけ
This is only 15,000 hectares
これはわずか15,000ヘクタールです
160 million hectares by 2011
2011年までに1億6,000万ヘクタール
9% of global renewable energy
世界の再生可能エネルギーの 9%
Now
現在
Genetic crops
遺伝子作物
He multiplied 10,000 times
彼は10,000倍にした
Think about the weak things that can make the world go like this
世界をこのようにしてしまう弱いものについて考えてください
Many countries go to the weak
多くの国が弱者の側に回る
He must be something that can stand the test
彼は試練に耐えられる人物に違いない
Otherwise, it is impossible for so many countries
そうでなければ、これほど多くの国では不可能です
in species
種の中で
And what about his production value?
そして彼の生産価値はどうなるのでしょうか？
is continuously rising until 2011
2011年まで上昇し続ける
What about the production value of the seeds?
種子の生産額はどうなるのでしょうか？
reached $12 billion
120億ドルに達した
This is an area below
ここは下のエリアです
Then there is the production value
次に生産額です
what crops are grown
どのような作物が栽培されているのか
The main ones are soybeans, corn, cotton and rapeseed
主なものは大豆、トウモロコシ、綿花、菜種です。
Soybeans are eaten by both animals and humans
大豆は動物も人間も食べる
corn is eaten by animals
トウモロコシは動物に食べられる
Cotton, clothes, and rapeseed are eaten by people
綿花、衣類、菜種が人に食べられる
Then this is the area where it is planted
そして、これが植えられているエリアです
One million hectares
100万ヘクタール
Then what
じゃあ何
What kind of features are most
どのような機能が多いのか
Anti-weed killer or anti-insect or double anti-
防草剤または防虫または二重防草
Now there are a lot of two features together
多くの 2 つの機能が一緒になっています
So insect resistance is what I just explained to you
防虫性については先ほど説明したとおりです
That protein of that BT
あのBTのあのプロテイン
I didn't talk about anti-weed killers in particular today
今日は特に除草剤の話はしませんでした
It also has many benefits
メリットもたくさんあります
But I want to say don't say it seems to be doing publicity for these companies
でも言いたいのは、これらの企業の宣伝をしているようだとは言わないでください
So I'm not talking about this in particular
だから、特にこれについては話していないんですが、
But it can be seen that
しかし、それを見ることができます
Its area is really rising
その面積は本当に増加しています
OK, this area has just been increased
OK、このエリアは拡張されたばかりです
we really tuned in
私たちは本当に同調しました
Where are the countries where the planting is distributed?
植栽が分布している国はどこですか?
These colored, colored countries
この色とりどりの色とりどりの国
is the country where it was planted
それが植えられた国です
By 2011 there were already 29 countries
2011年までにすでに29カ国があった
I have been teaching for so many years
私は何年も教えてきました
Almost every year I have to update
ほぼ毎年更新しなければなりません
must update why
更新する必要がある理由
Because almost two countries are added every year
毎年ほぼ2か国が追加されるため
the number of two countries
2つの国の数
that this
これは
this
これ
of course you look at me
もちろんあなたは私を見ています
The United States, of course, is the first
もちろんアメリカが初です
Canada
カナダ
Then this Sino-American
じゃあこの中国系アメリカ人は
then south american countries
それから南米諸国
Most of them are planted
ほとんどが植えられています
Then the mainland, India, South Africa, Australia
次に本土、インド、南アフリカ、オーストラリア
you see even this europe
このヨーロッパさえ見えますね
Several countries have planted
いくつかの国が植樹を行っている
Look like Sweden, Germany, Spain
スウェーデン、ドイツ、スペインに似てる
all kinds
すべての種類
OK
OK
so you can watch a trend
トレンドを監視できるようにする
Then
それから
Well, so many countries are doing
まあ、非常に多くの国がやっている
But many people still care
しかし、多くの人はまだ気にしています
This machine-modified crop is being used by our food and the environment
この機械的に組み換えられた作物は私たちの食糧と環境に利用されています
Safe, I want to do it again, there are many people
安心、またやりたい、人が多い
It's probably always been the same problem.
おそらくいつも同じ問題があったのでしょう。
Then we are here to explain to you
それでは、ここでご説明させていただきます
let's start by saying
言ってみましょう
Because we just had a rough idea of ​​what the machine modification is all about.
なぜなら、マシンの変更がどのようなものかを大まかに把握しただけだからです。
It's like putting a gene from the outside and then putting it in.
遺伝子を外から入れて、また中に入れるような感じです。
But let's find out first
でも、まずは調べてみましょう
In fact, our human body already has a lot of these
実際、私たち人間の体にはすでにこれらのものがたくさんあります
We just said that in the process of green seeding
グリーンシーディングの過程でと先ほど言いました
Many genes have been exchanged like this
多くの遺伝子はこのように交換されてきました
That plants, animals, including people, etc.
植物や動物、人も含めて、など。
That person, including people, some very important things
あの人も、人も、とても大切なもの
Let's first look at the cells of our human body
まずは人体の細胞を見てみましょう
Inside human cells Inside animal cells
人間の細胞の中 動物の細胞の中
There must be this green line
この緑の線があるはずです
But what about plants, it will have a
しかし、植物はどうでしょうか?
It's only for plants
植物専用です
neither animals
動物でもない
this is our nucleus
これが私たちの核です
Our genetic material is inside this nucleus
私たちの遺伝物質はこの核の中にあります
For plants it has this cell coin
植物の場合はこのセルコインがあります
But animals don't have this cell currency
しかし、動物にはこの携帯通貨がありません
These are two very important organs
これらは2つの非常に重要な器官です
Why do I mention these two organs in particular
なぜこの 2 つの臓器について特に言及するのか
Leaf lift phenomenon
葉律提跟力現象
Yelu mentioned that it needs to carry out photosynthesis
Yelu は光合成を行う必要があると述べた
so sun down
それで日が沈む
Then there is this carbon dioxide and water for photosynthesis
次に、光合成のための二酸化炭素と水があります
produce glucose
ブドウ糖を生成する
Glucose provides this force embodiment
グルコースはこの力の具体化を提供します
to generate energy
エネルギーを生成する
So our sugar photosynthesis
つまり、私たちの糖光合成は
Yeluti
イェルティ
Energy is generated by this force
この力によってエネルギーが発生します
All animals must have this power manifested
すべての動物はこの力を発揮しなければなりません
otherwise there is no way to live
そうでなければ生きる道がない
You can't live because you don't have energy
気力が無いと生きていけない
All plants must have both
すべての植物は両方を持っている必要があります
Yeluti
イェルティ
it has cuboid
直方体を持っています
That plant contributes a lot
あの植物は大いに貢献している
Before this teacher Wu Suxin
この呉淑新先生の前に
I guess he also said this knowledge
こんな知識も言ってたんだろうな
this inside our earth
これは私たちの地球の中にあります
all carbohydrates
すべての炭水化物
Almost all are produced by plants for us.
私たちのために、ほとんどすべてが植物によって作られています。
what we eat every day
私たちが毎日食べるもの
are produced by plants
植物によって生産される
multidimensional organisms
多次元生物
it depends on it
それはそれに依存します
so no plants
だから植物はありません
The world has probably
世界はおそらく
Only some dimensional creatures are left
一部の次元生物だけが残っている
those two organs
その二つの器官
Cells 2.7 billion years ago
27億年前の細胞
In fact, these two organs do not exist.
実際には、これら 2 つの器官は存在しません。
But I don't know under what circumstances
でもどういう状況でそうなるのか分からない
this our cells
これが私たちの細胞です
prokaryotic it is a prokaryotic cell
原核生物、それは原核細胞です
Originally from lower organisms
もともとは下等生物由来
it eats into the cuboid
直方体に食い込む
You can see that it contains this stereo
このステレオが含まれていることがわかります
And then there are some cells
そしていくつかの細胞があります
It's a leprosome that's actually a bacterium
ハンセン病って実は細菌なんです
Bacteria
細菌
After it eats the bacteria
細菌を食べた後
This bacterium becomes
この細菌はこうなります
In this cell it becomes a stroma
この細胞では間質になります
Then there are some cells
それからいくつかの細胞があります
it eats some algae
藻類を食べます
So what happens after the algae enters?
では、藻類が侵入した後はどうなるのでしょうか？
become this plant
この植物になる
it becomes leptin and chloroplast
レプチンと葉緑体になります
So plants can photosynthesize
植物は光合成できるので、
What about its primitive ancestor?
その原始的な祖先はどうなるのでしょうか？
from this photosynthetic bacterium
この光合成細菌から
So our current higher organisms
つまり、私たちの現在の高等生物は、
not just all kinds of animals
さまざまな動物だけでなく
including humans
人間も含めて
And this variety of plants
そして、この様々な植物は、
inside our cells
私たちの細胞の中
There are already some of its fire doctor creatures coming
すでに消防士の生き物がいくつか来ています
or genes from algae
または藻類の遺伝子
already inside us
すでに私たちの中に
So after so many years of evolution
長い年月の進化を経て
can coexist with us
私たちと共存できる
Then look at the natural world
それから自然界を見てください
what about all creatures
すべての生き物はどうですか
cells themselves
細胞そのもの
constantly evolving
常に進化する
you don't need to green it
緑色にする必要はありません
It's already evolving
もう進化してるよ
You see, there can be many, many butterflies
ほら、たくさんの蝶がいる可能性があります
Beetles can be very, very plentiful
カブトムシは非常にたくさん発生する可能性があります
Then what
じゃあ何
like this fish for example
たとえばこの魚のように
You are a fish and it can live well
あなたは魚です、そしてそれはよく生きることができます
What about two fish?
2匹の魚はどうでしょうか？
What about good friends getting married and having kids?
仲の良い友達が結婚して子供ができたらどうなるでしょうか？
produce a better fish to survive
生き残るためにより良い魚を生産する
then if you can't
それができないなら
have produced better fish
より良い魚を生産しました
Your original fish may not be competitive
元の魚は競争力がないかもしれません
this is irresponsible
これは無責任です
It turned out to be worse
もっと悪いことが判明した
was wiped out
全滅した
just die
ただ死ぬだけ
So in nature
だから自然界では
In fact, it is constantly
実際、それは常に
have been genetically between various organisms
遺伝的にさまざまな生物の間で存在してきた
Inside the creature
生き物の内部
Its genes are constantly changing
その遺伝子は常に変化しています
Except for this natural world
この自然界を除いて
natural mating
自然交配
among many other reasons
他の多くの理由の中でも
All living things are infected by viruses
すべての生き物はウイルスに感染します
What about the virus?
ウイルスはどうですか？
It also carries genes into our body
私たちの体に遺伝子を運ぶこともあります
then
それから
Collapsing into our genetic body
私たちの遺伝子の体に崩壊する
then become part of us
それから私たちの一部になってください
So actually you say that nature species
つまり、実際にあなたは自然種と言っています
In fact, the gene is constantly mixing
実際、遺伝子は常に混合しています
is a very natural phenomenon
それは非常に自然な現象です
OK so virus infection
よし、ウイルス感染か
It is also the constant mutation and evolution of this gene
それはまた、この遺伝子の絶え間ない突然変異と進化でもあります
a very important reason
非常に重要な理由
ok then let's find out
わかりました、それでは調べてみましょう
Well, this genetic change
さて、この遺伝子変化は
It's not really a terrible thing
本当は怖いことではないんです
Because nature is constantly happening
自然は常に起こっているので
But it's a real problem for us
しかし、それは私たちにとって本当の問題です
which means we eat these plants
つまり、私たちはこれらの植物を食べるのです
safe or not
安全かどうか
like a genetic plant before it goes to market
市場に出る前の遺伝子植物のようなもの
it will definitely do some experiments
それは間違いなくいくつかの実験を行うでしょう
Toxicity to animals Hypersensitivity
動物に対する毒性 過敏症
changes in nutrients, etc.
栄養素の変化など。
It has to go through these experiments
これらの実験を経る必要がある
I always say
私はいつも言います
These things are genetically modified
こういったものは遺伝子組み換えされています
There is nothing to be afraid of when you eat it in your stomach
お腹の中で食べれば怖いものはない
Why
なぜ
Because the main components are DNA and protein
主成分はDNAとタンパク質なので
Just like the rice we eat every day
私たちが毎日食べるお米と同じように
vegetables water
野菜 水
The ingredients are almost the same, after eating in the stomach
胃の中で食べた後、成分はほぼ同じです
inside your stomach
お腹の中
There are already a lot of this decomposing mold
この分解カビはすでにたくさんあります
Inside the Tuo Ye, Stomach Leaf, Chair Leaf, and Intestine Leaf
沱葉、胃葉、椅子葉、腸葉の内部
Just a lot of decomposing mold
カビが大量に腐ってるだけ
protein
タンパク質
There are protein molds, nucleic acid molds, etc.
タンパク質カビ、核酸カビなどがあります。
digested
消化された
Or the absorption of nutrients
あるいは吸収された栄養素
So, the genetic thing it's not
つまり、遺伝的なものではありません
Phytochemicals are not pesticides
ファイトケミカルは農薬ではありません
not this preservative
この防腐剤ではありません
not antibiotics
抗生物質ではありません
Not what these you fear will cause
あなたが恐れているこれらのことが引き起こすものではありません
something that accumulates or is harmful to a person
蓄積するもの、または人に有害なもの
Basically, it is digested in the stomach
基本的には胃で消化されます。
This experiment has done a lot
この実験は多くのことを成し遂げました
Animal experiments are done a lot
動物実験が頻繁に行われている
there is evidence
証拠があります
So actually we really are
それで実際に私たちは本当にそうです
Already eat a lot of genetic stuff
すでに遺伝物質をたくさん食べている
Although everyone has a question
誰もが疑問を持っているにもかかわらず、
That is to say, I ate genetically
つまり、遺伝的に食べた
Safety actually went on the market in 1996 until now
実際にセーフティが発売されたのは1996年で、現在に至るまで
we ate a lot
私たちはたくさん食べました
Because there are very few soybeans grown in Taiwan
台湾では大豆の栽培が非常に少ないため、
More than 90% of the vast majority are imported
その大部分の90％以上が輸入品です
mostly chicken wings
主に手羽先
Many bean products on the market are chicken wings
市場に出回っている大豆製品の多くは手羽先です
but we have rules
でも私たちにはルールがあります
If your protein content reaches 5%
タンパク質含有量が5％に達すると
you are going to sign
あなたは署名するつもりです
so you look carefully
だからよく見てください
you will see that it is written very small
非常に小さく書かれていることがわかります
write about genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えについて書きます
Of course there are some Chinese tofu now
もちろん中華豆腐もありますよ
Printed tofu is non-GMO
プリント豆腐は非遺伝子組み換えです
it writes big
大きく書いてある
Actually there is no need
実際にはその必要はない
don't worry about that
それについては心配しないでください
we really eat a lot
私たちは本当にたくさん食べます
There are many in the world
世界にはたくさんあります
Human experiments have been done for more than 10 years
人体実験は10年以上も行われてきた
no problem
問題ない
so don't worry about these things
だからこれらのことは心配しないでください
what are you really worried about
本当に何を心配しているのですか
I go to see it every time
毎回見に行ってます
look at this
これを見てください
What is facial agent
美顔剤とは
It's just a chemical.
それはただの化学物質です。
and what preservatives
そして防腐剤は何ですか
biphasic acid
二相酸
Then what is the cost of acid and so on
それでは、酸などのコストはいくらですか？
actually a lot
実際にはたくさん
if you can look carefully
注意深く見ることができれば
Many foods actually contain these
実際に多くの食品にこれらが含まれています
bring these to the government there are regulations
規制があるのでこれらを政府に提出してください
But is it really at home according to the rules?
しかし、本当にルール通りに家にいるのでしょうか？
not very clear
あまり明確ではない
In fact, often still
実際、今でも多くの場合、
Occasionally it's on the news
たまにニュースにもなるけど
So I will also buy
じゃあ私も買います
try to buy this
これを買ってみてください
fog chill preservative stuff
フォグチル防腐剤
so this
したがって、この
this is a worry
これは心配です
don't worry about this
これについては心配しないでください
don't need to worry that much
そんなに心配する必要はありません
good
良い
Then we just mentioned that
それから、先ほども言いましたが、
the effect on the environment
環境への影響
This is on the biosafety assessment
これはバイオセーフティー評価に関するものです
will definitely do
必ずやります
So we already mentioned
したがって、すでに述べました
This crop like their insect-resistant
この作物は害虫に強いのが好きです
For this helpful sleepy bug
この便利な眠そうなバグについては、
actually very good
実際にとても良い
so what
だから何
Definitely do some field biosecurity assessments
現場でのバイオセキュリティ評価を必ず行う
For example, will he turn into a weed?
たとえば、彼は雑草になるでしょうか？
Possibility of interbreeding with Jinyuan weeds
金源雑草との交雑の可能性
morbid relationship
病的な関係
Relationships with other intentional insects, animals, etc.
他の意図的な昆虫、動物などとの関係。
So it's actually under the magnifying glass
実際に虫眼鏡の下で
View to be able to list
一覧できるビュー
Pollen spread is of course possible.
花粉の飛散も当然考えられます。
This is something that many groups keep coming up with.
これは多くのグループが考え出し続けていることです
he said you would spread
彼はあなたが広めると言いました
that's actually possible
それは実際に可能です
But this can be done by a lot of management
しかし、これは多くの管理者によって実行できます
Then we'll review the management later
後ほど管理を見直します
Is this pesticide spraying?
これは農薬散布ですか？
That is to say, those crops that are resistant to insects
つまり、害虫に強い作物です。
Will it be a problem with intentional insects?
意図的に虫を入れた場合は問題ないでしょうか？
we have just explained
先ほど説明しました
The results done so far show
これまでに行われた結果は次のとおりです
there's nothing wrong with it
何も問題ありません
I'm sorry
ごめんなさい
So this pollen will spread
この花粉が飛散するので、
in what way
どのような方法で
This is an experiment done by Farming
これはファーミングが行った実験です
you just have to fence it around
周りを柵で囲うだけでいい
Or you give it enough isolation space
または、十分な隔離スペースを与えます
It can separate the pollen
花粉を分離できる
This is rice research
お米の研究です
You can put genetically modified ones together
遺伝子組み換えのものを組み合わせることができます
a piece of non-genetically modified
非遺伝子組み換えのもの
If there is this green mud in the middle, it will be surrounded
真ん中にこの緑の泥があれば 囲まれてしまう
Its streaming rate is 0
ストリーミング レートは 0 です
And what about the distance
そして距離はどうなるのか
It's completely 0 at about 40 meters
40メートルくらいで完全に0です
At 35 meters, there will be very little
35メートルではほとんど何もありません
The odds are pretty cool
確率はかなりいいです
So in fact the fill-in experiment
実際、穴埋め実験は
You have to do these things to be listed
リストに掲載されるためにはこれらのことを行う必要があります
So we finally mention that
それで、最後にそれについて言及します
Is genetic food safe?
遺伝子組み換え食品は安全ですか?
Yes
はい
Because they have undergone strict animal safety assessment
厳格な動物安全性評価を受けているため
Then there is one more important thing to say
それから、もう一つ重要な事があります
a lot of this bone
この骨がたくさん
Because insects will eat and have wounds later
後で虫に食われて傷が付くから
then it grows syringa
それから成長します syringa
Aflatoxin
アフラトキシン
This is a very serious factor that can cause cancer
これは癌を引き起こす可能性のある非常に深刻な要因です
so we sometimes eat this peanut
だから私たちは時々このピーナッツを食べます
Especially peanuts imported from Southeast Asia
特に東南アジアから輸入される落花生
be careful
気をつけて
Maybe there are some plums in it
梅も入ってるかも
xanthotoxin
キサントトキシン
Then if you eat it, it will cause cancer
じゃあ食べるとガンになるよ
it's a terrible thing
それはひどいことだ
but they found
しかし彼らは見つけた
Since these corns with this insect resistance
このトウモロコシはこの害虫耐性を持っているので、
The ratio of producing this aflatoxin is greatly reduced
このアフラトキシンの生成比率が大幅に低下します。
So it's not just pesticide reduction
つまり、単に農薬を減らすだけではありません
It also does not produce aflatoxin
アフラトキシンも生成しません
Nutrients can then be added
その後、栄養素を追加することができます
Then it can correspond to the rapidly increasing population
そうすれば人口急増にも対応できる
for us in taiwan
台湾の私たちにとって
This kind of effect can resist insects and diseases
この種の効果は害虫や病気に抵抗することができます
is actually very important
実はとても重要です
Why?
なぜ？
In European and American countries, they are heavily valued
欧米諸国では非常に高く評価されています
He wants something like wet stacking or using pesticides or something
彼はウェットスタッキングや殺虫剤の使用などを望んでいます
It's all done by airplanes
それはすべて飛行機によって行われます
Or he has this automatic irrigation system
あるいは彼は自動灌漑システムを持っています
But in Southeast Asian countries
しかし東南アジア諸国では
Much like Taiwan
台湾によく似ています
Many farmers still use their own spray
多くの農家は今でも独自のスプレーを使用しています
Look, the farmer probably didn't bring anything.
ほら、農夫はおそらく何も持ってきていないでしょう。
this security
このセキュリティ
This is still very common
これは今でも非常に一般的です
If you really want to play defense
本気で守備をしたいなら
it's ok
大丈夫です
But is it possible for farmers to do this?
しかし、農家がこれを行うことは可能でしょうか？
All seem to be preventing and treating SARS
全員がSARSの予防と治療を行っているようだ
This is a potato chip from the mainland
これは本土のポテトチップスです
them
彼ら
I don't know how they really defend
彼らが実際にどうやって守っているのか分からない
very strange
非常に奇妙な
OK
OK
anything else
他に何か
Taiwan is actually better now
今の台湾はむしろ良くなった
That is to say, there are some rooted systems
つまり、root化されたシステムがいくつかあります。
there is a special
特別なものがあります
Because our villages are aging now
私たちの村は今、高齢化が進んでいるから
Many farmers are also farming, but they can't move too much.
農家も農業をやっている人が多いのですが、あまり動けません。
So let others do it
だから他の人にやらせてください
Then what
じゃあ何
In fact, there are some better technical
実際にはもっと優れた技術的なものがあります
Progressive
プログレッシブ
It's to use an unmanned aircraft to accompany you.
それは、無人航空機を同行させることです。
So Taiwan is now also like this
さて、台湾もこんな感じになりました
but think about it
でも考えてみてください
Is it possible that in the future every farmer will be at the edge of the field
将来、すべての農家が畑の端にいるようになる可能性はありますか?
shake the plane there
そこで飛行機を揺さぶる
silly pesticide
愚かな殺虫剤
I think it would be interesting if there was a day
日があったら面白いと思います
really passed
本当に通りました
But then again
しかし、またしても
Can we avoid pen and pesticide
ペンと殺虫剤を避けることができますか
Actually it's the most important
実はそれが一番重要なのです
Because you need to use pesticides to pen pesticides
殺虫剤を使用するには殺虫剤を使用する必要があるため
It takes money and energy
お金もエネルギーもかかる
then pollute the environment
それから環境を汚染する
Then what
じゃあ何
Mostly farmers
ほとんどが農家
farmers hurt the most
農民が最も被害を受ける
In fact, every year there are farmers
実際、毎年農家がいます。
Poisoning yourself from pen pesticides
ペン用殺虫剤による中毒
so this
したがって、この
or let the plants themselves
または植物そのものに任せてください
resistant to illness
病気に強い
Its benefits are much more
その利点はさらに多くあります
That plus the amount of pesticides used in Taiwan
これに台湾で使用される農薬の量を加えたもの
2.5 times the Asian average
アジア平均の2.5倍
5 times that of the US
米国の5倍
very scary
とても怖い
Because Taiwan is hot and humid
台湾は高温多湿なので
Therefore, those who are particularly prone to long-term weaving are seriously ill
したがって、特に長時間織り続ける傾向がある人は重篤な病気になります。
So I think Taiwan needs to develop
だから台湾は発展する必要があると思う
The crop of experience like this
このような経験の収穫
but what about our government
しかし、私たちの政府はどうでしょうか
What about our entire Council of Agriculture?
私たちの農業委員会全体はどうですか？
civil service system
公務員制度
they can
彼らはできる
This is less wrong
これは間違いが少ないです
this less
これより少ない
once more is worse than once less
もう一度のほうが一回未満より悪い
Then it's better not to worry about anything
それなら何も気にしないほうがいいよ
So many of our
私たちの非常に多くの
Taiwan's technology is actually very good
台湾の技術は本当に優れています
we have a lot of good this
私たちには良いものがたくさんある
This product of genetic engineering
この遺伝子工学の産物は
not easy to market
市場に出すのは簡単ではない
I think our agriculture
私たちの農業は
National import chemist
国内輸入化学者
Or agricultural fertility industry plan
あるいは農業豊饒産業計画
our people
私たちの人々
Professor Wu Jinglie is here
ウー・ジンリー教授が来ました
he deeply understands
彼は深く理解しています
This one from Taiwan
こちらは台湾産
The potential of our researchers is very good
私たちの研究者のポテンシャルは非常に優れています
We can have many good products
良い製品がたくさんあります
Just told Ang Lee
アン・リーに言ったところです
We have a lot of this in Taiwan
台湾にはこれがたくさんあります
People who work in the electric business industry
電気事業業界にお勤めの方
very talented
非常優秀
But there is no way to play
でも遊ぶ方法がない
Why
なぜ
think about this
これについて考えます
good
良い
So I am very concerned about this issue
ですから、私はこの問題について非常に懸念しています
So I often write articles
なのでよく記事を書きます
Then what
じゃあ何
strangeness
奇妙さ
His computer will run by itself today
彼のコンピュータは今日から自動的に動作します
Eh
えー
Oops
おっと
OK
OK
i will write
私は書く
GM crops
基改作物
this is me
これが私です
This was about two years ago
これは約2年前のことです
then in china
それから中国で
I just published
たった今公開しました
I said whether machine-modified crops are the hope of Taiwan's agriculture
機械組み換え作物は台湾農業の希望なのかと私は言いました
But it must be expected
しかし、それは予想されているはずです
There must be an objection soon
すぐに反対意見が出てくるはずだ
Machine-modified crops still come and should be dealt with
機械で組み換えられた作物は今でも出現しており、対処する必要がある
So the professor at National Taiwan University
そこで国立台湾大学の教授は、
Academician He Danghua
学者何ダンファ
He also wrote an article
彼も記事を書きました
He said that this machine-modified crop is due to rational discussion
彼は、この機械改変作物は合理的な議論によるものであると述べた
what is the most important
最も重要なことは何ですか
Because we really haven't had a rational discussion
本当に合理的な議論ができていないから
Everyone is open and transparent
誰もがオープンで透明性がある
The pros and cons
長所と短所
discuss it
それについて話し合う
let everyone know
みんなに知らせて
Then we choose
それから私たちは選択します
should we do this
こうすべきか
You let me choose experience not to spray pesticides
農薬散布をしない体験を選ばせてもらいました
It's still a non-experienced person who doesn't spray pesticides
農薬散布はまだ未熟者です
I think I have to choose experience instead of spraying pesticides
農薬散布ではなく経験を選択する必要があると思います
real
本物
After we understand his nature
彼の性質を理解した上で
I also recently wrote an article
私も最近記事を書きました
That is to say, machine-modified crops are actually a political issue.
つまり、機械組み換え作物は実は政治問題なのです。
real
本物
We just talked about a lot of issues
私たちはちょうどたくさんの問題について話しました
if you scientifically
科学的に言えば
he's not a problem
彼は問題ないよ
But this government
しかしこの政府は
Between countries is often because of political factors
国家間では政治的要因が原因となることが多い
So he will block his development
だから彼は自分の成長を妨げるだろう
very pity
とても残念です
what are the consequences of this
この結果は何ですか
you won't let me
あなたは私を許さないでしょう
look first
まず見てください
Look at this anti-pest and disease-resistant words
この害虫や病気に強い言葉を見てください。
You have a lot of pesticides
農薬をたくさん持っています
who makes money
誰がお金を稼ぐのか
Pesticide companies make money
農薬会社は儲かる
so what
だから何
You crop that prevents us from developing these experiences
私たちがこれらの経験を積むのを妨げるのはあなたです
You are helping the pesticide company
あなたは農薬会社を助けています
anything else
他に何か
Gold just now and you too
さっきのゴールド、あなたも同じよ
2 million for experiment
実験に200万
20 million for biosafety assessment
バイオセーフティ評価に2000万
I have been doing it for ten years and finally found that there is no problem at all.
10年ほど続けてきて、ようやく全く問題ないことが分かりました。
really no problem at all
本当に全く問題ありません
but who did you help
でも誰を助けたの？
You helped those agbiotech companies
あなたはアグバイオテクノロジー企業を支援しました
The world's largest agricultural biotechnology companies
世界最大の農業バイオテクノロジー企業
Because only he can afford 20 million to do it
それをするのに2000万も出せるのは彼だけだから
biosafety assessment
このようなバイオセーフティ評価
Many of our small laboratories
私たちの小規模な研究室の多くは
small company
小さな会社
spend so much money to do this
これをするのにとてもお金を使います
so who did you help
それで誰を助けたのですか
You just helped the big companies
大企業を助けただけだよ
Only he has money to do things
彼だけが何かをするためのお金を持っている
so why now
それでなぜ今
Make money by experience crops
経験作物でお金を稼ぐ
those big companies
それらの大企業
So this has a lot to think about
したがって、これには考えなければならないことがたくさんあります
then i have been
それから私は行ってきました
In addition, it has been emphasized that
さらに、次のように強調されています。
why should we hurry
なぜ急ぐ必要があるのか
Actively do research
積極的に研究を行う
Although our government does not promote
私たちの政府は推進していませんが、
but he
でも彼は
He can still let us do research
彼はまだ私たちに研究をさせてくれる
Guo Kewei
郭克偉
he is really nice
彼は本当に素敵です
That is to say, there is still a lot of money
つまり、まだお金がたくさんあるということです
let's do research
研究をしましょう
because we really want to master
本当にマスターしたいから
Hold this upstream patent
この上流特許を保持する
upgrade
アップグレード
Our IT industry is already suffering
私たちのIT業界はすでに苦境に立たされています
There are many upstream patents that cannot be grasped
把握できない上流特許が多数ある
so what
だから何
Every hundred dollars you sell
あなたが売る100ドルごとに
mobile phone is likely these
携帯電話はおそらくこれです
like iphone
像iPhone
This Apple makes fifty bucks
このアップルは50ドル儲かります
Taiwan probably only earns one or two dollars
台湾はおそらく1ドルか2ドルしか稼いでいない
Patents are in the hands of others
特許は他人の手に渡っている
So biotechnology is the same
バイオテクノロジーも同じです
Especially the good genes of this crop now
特に今のこの作物の優れた遺伝子
if you look online
オンラインで見たら
A lot of genes every day
毎日たくさんの遺伝子が
Patented by these biotech companies
これらのバイオテクノロジー企業が特許を取得
If we don't speed up our research
研究をスピードアップしないと
In the future, we will use it ourselves in Taiwan
将来的には台湾でも使用していきます
You have to pay other people's money
他人のお金を支払わなければなりません
So this is a pretty stressful thing
なので、これはかなりのストレスです
so why we've been active
ではなぜ私たちが活動してきたのか
doing these research and development
これらの研究開発を行っている
In fact, many scientists around the world
実際、世界中の多くの科学者が
Both support this genetically modified crop
どちらもこの遺伝子組み換え作物をサポートしています
this is just an example
これはほんの一例です
American Institute for Employment
アメリカ雇用研究所
Royal Society
王立協会
In fact, if you look online
実際にネットで調べてみると
There are many, many groups like this that are very supportive
こういった協力的な団体はたくさんあります
Finally I want to tell this story
最後にこの話をします
This is January 5 this year
今年の1月5日です
Newsweek posted a message
ニューズウィークがメッセージを投稿しました
many people don't notice
多くの人は気づいていない
He posted such a photo
こんな写真を投稿してくれました
Metro in Paris, France on February 15, 2011
2011 年 2 月 15 日、フランス、パリの地下鉄
Photo taken at the subway station
地下鉄の駅によると
You see he uses this corn as a gun
彼はこのトウモロコシを銃として使っているのがわかります
to hit someone on the head
人の頭を殴る
So I think what he means is probably
だから彼が言いたいのはおそらく次のようなことだと思います
I don't understand this French
このフランス語はわかりません
I think some students are from France
フランスから来た学生もいると思います
He might understand this
彼はそれを理解しているかもしれない
I mean genetically modified stuff
遺伝子組み換えのものって言うのは
It seems that if you eat people, what will happen?
人を食べるとどうなるらしい？
what will happen if you die
あなたが死んだらどうなりますか
So he put a picture like this
そこで彼はこんな写真を載せました
But his article
しかし彼の記事は
What is New Swick really going to talk about
ニュー・スウィックは本当に何を話すつもりですか
He wants to talk about this gentleman
彼はこの紳士について話したいと思っています
Called Mark Nymus
マーク・ナイマスと呼ばれる
this mr.
この先生。
this gentleman said
この紳士は言いました
he was surprised
彼は驚いた
Mr. He apologized
彼氏は謝罪した
sorry for what
何のために残念
for him for many years
長年にわたって彼にとって
Probably more than twenty years
おそらく二十年以上は経つだろう
Anti-gene behavior like this
このような抗遺伝子の動作
Everyone is surprised why
なぜかみんなびっくり
Because he is a very famous environmentalist
彼は非常に有名な環境活動家なので、
I have been anti-experience, I have been advocating
私は反経験を主張してきました
Can't eat this experience
この経験は食べられない
then he apologized
それから彼は謝った
Then this article in this Newsweek
それから、このニューズウィークのこの記事
He's saying experience won't be a problem for us
彼は私たちにとって経験は問題にならないと言っている
your real problem now
今のあなたの本当の問題
where is the real crisis
本当の危機はどこにあるのか
but the minority in rich countries
しかし裕福な国では少数派
He insisted on eating very natural food
彼は非常に自然な食べ物を食べることにこだわった
But in the future, they will fight back because of their behavior
しかし、将来、彼らは自分たちの行動のために反撃するでしょう
You will starve many, many people around the world
世界中でたくさんの人が飢えることになるだろう
So in his article
それで彼の記事では
This has this website here
ここにこのウェブサイトがあります
So the main question is to go back to what I just said
それで、主な質問は、私が今言ったことに戻ることです
Now the global food article is getting bigger
現在、世界の食品に関する記事はますます大きくなっています
And this Mark Niners
そしてこのマーク・ナイナーズ
He's a real environmentalist
彼は真の環境活動家だ
He was born in Oxford, England, quite young
彼はイギリスのオックスフォードでかなり若くして生まれました
he is a famous writer
彼は有名な作家です
journalists and environmentalists
ジャーナリストと環境活動家
I've also written many books and made movies.
彼はまた、多くの本を書き、映画も制作しました。
mostly related to issues of environmental change
主に環境変化の問題に関連する
In a recent public lecture in Oxford, England, he
イギリスのオックスフォードで行われた最近の公開講演で、彼はこう言った。
Publicly apologized for his anti-GN actions since the 1990s
1990年代以来の反GN行動を公に謝罪
Because he thinks that as an environmentalist
彼は環境活動家としてそう考えているから
This new technology will be mindful of the global environment
地球環境に配慮した新技術
When he first heard about Mansanto's GN soybeans
マンサント社のGN大豆について初めて聞いたとき
He thinks this product will pollute food and our environment
彼はこの製品が食品と環境を汚染すると考えています
It is something that cannot be done with high technology
高度な技術では出来ない事です
what a nightmare
なんという悪夢
So they started spreading the fear
それで彼らは恐怖を広め始めました
like wildfire
山火事のように
Made GN Friday almost banned in Europe within a few years
GNフライデーは数年以内にヨーロッパでほぼ禁止になった
This fear is also exported by the Calendar Peace Organization and Friends of the Earth
この恐怖は、カレンダー平和機構とフレンズ・オブ・ジ・アースによっても広められています。
to Africa, India, Asia
アフリカ、インド、アジアへ
The development of genetic organization is affected
遺伝子組織の発達が影響を受ける
This Mark thinks his activity
このマークは自分の活動を考えています
It's the most successful event he's ever been involved in
それは彼がこれまで参加した中で最も成功したイベントだ
most successful sport
最も成功したスポーツ
What about after 2008?
2008年以降はどうでしょうか？
someone asked him
誰かが彼に尋ねた
He says you're against agribiotech
彼はあなたがアグリバイオテクノロジーに反対していると言っています
because of opposition to agribiotech companies
アグリバイオテクノロジー企業への反対のため
you against genes
あなたは遺伝子に反対します
So will you also be against big car companies?
では、あなたも大手自動車会社に反対するつもりですか？
And against the car?
そして車に対して？
So this time he started
そこで今回彼は始めました
learn from science
科学から学ぶ
Causes of Environmental Change
環境変化の原因
Meaning with experience crops
経験作物の意味
Then his warship found
すると彼の軍艦が見つかった
Empirical technology can indeed solve
経験的テクノロジーは確かに解決できる
Rapidly deteriorating environmental change and population issues
急速に悪化する環境変化と人口問題
Just like the issues I mentioned earlier in my speech today
今日のスピーチで先ほど述べた問題と同じように、
in his article
彼の記事の中で
All written into a very long article
すべてが非常に長い記事に書かれています
So we scientifically
そこで私たちは科学的に
look at this question
この質問を見てください
Experience definitely pays off
経験は必ず報われます
that to our future world
それは私たちの未来の世界へ
it is needed
それが必要とされています
it may not solve all problems
すべての問題を解決できるわけではないかもしれない
But we don't have much choice now
しかし、今はあまり選択肢がありません
We still have to hurry up and develop this technology
私たちはまだこの技術の開発を急がなければなりません
let it provide us with safety
私たちに安全を与えてください
Then this can protect the environment
そうすれば環境を守ることができる
Then it can cope with the future population
そうすれば将来の人口に対応できる
a very important strategy
非常に重要な戦略
ok then i'll end up here
はい、それではここで終わります
I believe us scientists
私たちは科学者を信じています
No one wants to hurt anyone
誰も誰かを傷つけたくありません
We all want to say that based on good science
私たちは皆、良い科学に基づいてそう言いたいのです
to make the greatest contribution to mankind
人類に最大限の貢献をするために
so thank you guys
ありがとうございます
Thanks
ありがとう
The first time I came to the professor to check the examination
初めて試験をチェックするために教授のところに来たとき
He's dreamed about the time
彼はその時のことを夢見ていた
Usually I just move on as soon as it's out
いつもは終わったらすぐに続けるんだけど
I am doing textbooks today
今日は教科書をやっています
our ten minute chance
私たちの10分間のチャンス
or the end of the ninety-sixty minutes
あるいは960分の終わり
so we ask
そこで私たちは尋ねます
I'm sorry to ask Professor Yu
ユウ先生にお願いして申し訳ありません。
i ask simple questions
私は簡単な質問をします
that means we buy food
それは私たちが食べ物を買うことを意味します
When buying fruits and vegetables, do you buy the ones you have never eaten?
果物や野菜を買うとき、今まで食べたことのないものを買いますか？
It will be safer to eat like this
こうやって食べたほうが安心だよ
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, many people will ask this question
はい、多くの人がこの質問をするでしょう
Of course that shows
もちろんそれは示しています
it is possible to show that
それを示すことは可能です
Pesticides may be used less
農薬の使用量が減る可能性がある
but how much is it really used
しかし、実際にどれくらい使っているのでしょうか？
I think it's still hard to say
まだ言いにくいと思います
and then the other one is
そしてもう一つは
We have a lot of bugs now
現在バグがたくさんあります
already resistant
すでに耐性がある
So you can't kill him with spray
だからスプレーで殺すことはできない
so it will die
だから死ぬだろう
So it's really the best
だから本当に最高なんです
better i think
最高だと思います
Plants themselves are resistant to insects and pesticides
植物自体が害虫や農薬に強い
still more important
さらに重要な
But someone still has a potential problem
しかし、まだ潜在的な問題を抱えている人がいます
That is to say, sometimes these bugs
つまり、時々これらのバグが発生するのです
germs it hardens
細菌が固まる
So it is not easy for you to come across a good breed
そのため、良い品種に出会うのは簡単ではありません
Not long after, the ingredient disease came again
それから間もなく、また成分病がやって来ました
But the traditional breed is worse
しかし、伝統的な品種はもっと悪いです
Sometimes it takes you 10 years
場合によっては10年かかることもある
meet a species
種に出会う
two or three years to come
２、３年はかかるだろうね
Came because of serious illness
重い病気のため来ました
But at least we now have genetic engineering to compete with it
しかし、少なくとも私たちは今、それに対抗できる遺伝子工学を持っています。
race it
レースしましょう
see who is faster
誰が速いかを見てください
you get very sick and get sick fast
あなたはとても病気になり、すぐに病気になります
I am also very fast with my genetic modification technology
遺伝子組み換え技術も非常に速いです
So at least we still have some strategy to follow it
したがって、少なくとも私たちはそれに従うための戦略をまだ持っています
deal with it like this
このように対処します
please tell me
教えてください
When I buy soybeans, I always buy the one with the fat gene.
私は大豆を買うときは必ず太る遺伝子を持つものを買います。
Is there no need to do this anymore?
もうこれを行う必要はありませんか？
I think there should be no need to worry about that
それは心配しなくてもいいと思いますよ
because we eat a lot
私たちはたくさん食べるので
you are at home of course you can do this
あなたは家にいるので、もちろんこれを行うことができます
But we know that there are really many people who eat out
でも外食する人が本当に多いのは知っています
What do we people who eat out eat out every day?
私たち外食派は毎日何を外食しているのでしょうか？
really don't know
本当に分からない
Genetic soybeans are still cheaper
遺伝子組み換え大豆はまだ安い
So I believe that many business people will still buy that kind of
ですから、多くのビジネスパーソンは今後もそのようなものを購入すると思います。
right
右
The most important thing is that he has been from 1996 to now
最も重要なことは、彼が 1996 年から現在まで活動し続けているということです。
It's been 16 years
16年経ちました
16 years have passed
16年が経ちました
I believe we have many things on the market
市場にはたくさんのものがあると思います
including a lot of medical stuff
医療関連のものも多く含まれています
No one can guarantee 100% that there will be no problems.
問題がないことを 100% 保証できる人はいません。
But in fact, the genetic thing is up to now
しかし実際には、遺伝的なものは現在まで続いています
really didn't happen a problem
本当に問題は起きなかった
right
右
grateful
感謝
OK
OK
teacher please
先生お願いします
How can we prevent certain
どうすれば特定のことを防ぐことができますか
Similar to Monsanto
モンサント社に似ている
Because they're pretty notorious.
だって彼らは本当に悪名高いんです。
That is, he has a lot of varieties
つまり、彼はたくさんの種類を持っています
He is the one who protected himself
自分を守ってくれたのは彼だった
If so
もしそうなら
Countries should develop biotechnology
各国はバイオテクノロジーを開発すべきだ
also a big problem
大きな問題でもある
In fact, there are many genes
実は遺伝子はたくさんある
there are many more available
他にもたくさんあります
It's not that only the genes he used can be used
自分が使った遺伝子だけが使えるわけではない
So why should we all step up our research
ではなぜ私たちは研究を強化する必要があるのでしょうか
that's it
それでおしまい
But what?
でも何？
Too bad only these big companies have money
残念なことに、お金を持っているのはこれらの大企業だけです
Can be pushed from R&D to product
研究開発から製品への推進が可能
he can
彼はできる
Get through every level and every level like this
このようにしてすべてのレベルとすべてのレベルを通過してください
but what about us
しかし、私たちについてはどうですか
Compared with these small companies with no money
お金のない中小企業に比べれば
small research institute
小さな研究所
you have to start from scratch
ゼロから始めなければなりません
It's really tough
本当に大変です
So the government is in terms of policy
つまり政府は政策面で
on the counseling
カウンセリングの上で
still have to play an important role
まだ重要な役割を果たさなければならない
Now the most important thing is to say
さて、最も重要なことは言うことです
If you know the nature of this gene
この遺伝子の性質がわかれば
If you don't use such strict standards
そんなに厳しい基準を使わないと
Taiwanese
台湾人
genetic criteria
遺伝的基準
I think it is almost the strictest in the world now
今はほぼ世界で最も厳しいと思う
real
本物
Now
現在
In fact, everything in Taiwan depends on Japan
実際、台湾のすべては日本に依存しています
why did we go
なぜ私たちは行ったのか
It seems that everyone has an excuse
みんな言い訳があるみたいだ
Talk about our rice in Taiwan or something
台湾のお米の話とか
Can't have genes
遺伝子は持てない
Because we sell it to Japan
日本に売ってるから
Japan will not buy it or something
日本は買わないとかなんとか
you in that papaya
そのパパイヤの中のあなた
Prof. Yi Xidong from Taiwan's famous Sino-British University
台湾の有名な中英大学のYi Xidong教授
antiviral papaya
抗ウイルスパパイヤ
After he developed more than ten years ago
彼が10年以上前に発症した後、
At that time, papayas in Taiwan were almost extinct.
当時、台湾のパパイヤはほぼ絶滅していました。
only later to the east
あとになって東へ
Because of the barrier of important mountains
大切な山の結界のせいで
can also hit a little bit
少し打つこともできる
but later
でもその後
Teacher Ye's Hard Papaya
イー先生のハードパパイヤ
Field experiment conducted by Zhongzai Agriculture
中財農業による圃場実験
The farmer saw that his papaya was growing well
農夫は自分のパパイヤが順調に成長しているのを見た
All other papayas are dead, only he is good
他のパパイヤはすべて死んでしまい、彼だけが元気です
stole the seeds
種を盗んだ
then go back to plant
それから工場に戻ります
So a few years ago Zhao Yongqing legislator
それで数年前、趙永清議員は
I still remember to ask
聞いたことを今でも覚えています
He said why Taiwan now heard that the test
彼は、なぜ台湾が今その実験を聞いたのかを語った。
One-third to one-quarter of papayas are
パパイヤの3分の1から4分の1は、
GM's might be even higher
GMはもっと高いかもしれない
because almost for a while
ほぼしばらくの間だから
Now we have papaya because
今はパパイヤがあるので、
Article scraping relationship
記事スクレイピング関係
So his GM papaya farmer went planting
そこで彼のGMパパイヤ農家は植え付けに行きました
Then, don’t many of our farmers go to the mainland to grow agricultural products?
では、農家の多くは本土に農産物を作りに行っているのではないでしょうか？
So he brought his chicken papaya to the mainland to plant
そこで彼は鶏のパパイヤを本土に持ち帰って植えました。
Then Mr. Ye went to Hainan Island
それから葉さんは海南島へ行きました
He went to the supermarket to buy a papaya
彼はパパイヤを買うためにスーパーマーケットへ行きました
dig out the seeds
種を掘り出す
Go to a supermarket in Beijing for a meeting
北京のスーパーマーケットに打ち合わせに行く
He bought another papaya and dug up that seed
彼は別のパパイヤを購入し、その種を掘り出しました
When he came back to Taiwan and checked, it was his papaya
台湾に戻って確認すると、それは彼のパパイヤだった
Hehehe
ふふふ
So the mainland is already eating everywhere
つまり本土はすでにどこでも食い物をしている
Then Hawaii developed at about the same time as him
そしてハワイは彼とほぼ同時期に発展した
Genetically engineered papayas are also virus-resistant
遺伝子組み換えパパイヤはウイルス耐性もある
It has been commercialized for ten years
商品化されて10年になります
As for Taiwan, he is constantly being suppressed and blocked.
台湾に関して言えば、彼は常に抑圧され、ブロックされています。
Then our chairman of the Agricultural Committee said
そこで農業委員長がこう言いました。
look at this
これを見てください
This is because Japanese papayas are all from Hawaii
日本のパパイヤはすべてハワイ産だからです
for export
輸出用
He said you see Japanese people don't even eat Hawaiian papayas
彼は、日本人はハワイのパパイヤさえ食べないのがわかると言いました
So how about this, we cannot develop in Taiwan
それでどうですか、台湾では開発できません
so really for a while
本当にしばらくの間
Hawaii had to be special for Japan
日本にとってハワイは特別な存在だった
Because he has many islands
島がたくさんあるから
So on the island he has, he specially planted this
そこで彼は所有する島々に特別にこれを植えました。
Airplane colorful papaya
飛行機のカラフルなパパイヤ
Export to Japan, right?
日本にも輸出されているのでしょうか？
But the September of the previous year
しかし前年の9月
Japan has passed the import
日本は輸入を通過しました
Hawaii's genetically modified papaya
ハワイの遺伝子組み換えパパイヤ
Our papaya is still pressed there
私たちのパパイヤはまだそこで圧搾されています
Biotechnology is actually progressing very fast
バイオテクノロジーは実際に非常に急速に進歩しています
everyone is competing
誰もが競争している
We are often treated like this by the government
私たちは政府からよくこのように扱われます
After pressing down
押し下げた後
Our competitiveness is lost
競争力が失われる
So this genetic thing
つまり、この遺伝的なものは
This big company has his deep pockets
この大企業は潤沢な資金を持っている
But also because of the help of environmental groups
しかし、それは環境保護団体の支援のおかげでもあります。
So it is still only the big companies that can
したがって、大企業しかなれない
able to dominate the market
市場を支配できる
Thanks
ありがとう
During GM, we should talk about native species of biodiversity
GM では、生物多様性の在来種について話し合う必要があります。
How can we find this balance
このバランスはどうすれば見つけられるでしょうか
i want biodiverse people
私は生物多様性のある人々が欲しいです
Of course, I hope to be able to find things in nature
もちろん、自然の中で何かを見つけることができればいいのですが、
don't change too much
あまり変えないでください
But I just mentioned that many
しかし、先ほど言いましたが、多くの
In fact, it keeps changing
実は変化し続けているんです
We humans add some genes to this crop
私たち人間はこの作物にいくつかの遺伝子を追加します
Then we're between different balances
それから私たちは異なるバランスの間にいます
exchange it
交換してください
In fact, we are promoting diversity
実際、私たちはダイバーシティを推進しています
So it's not reducing diversity
つまり、多様性が減少するわけではありません
Instead, it promotes diversity
むしろ多様性を促進する
This human looks like this
この人間はこんな感じ
This creature has evolved over the years
この生き物は長い年月をかけて進化してきた
In fact, many processes
実際には多くのプロセスが
Of course not anytime soon
もちろんすぐには無理ですが
it's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
Our humans are just speeding it up now
私たち人類は今、そのスピードを加速させているだけです
In fact, there are many things in nature
実は自然界にはいろんなものがあるんです
it's been happening
それは起こっている
Then I think if the population is not increasing so fast
人口がそれほど急速に増加していないと思います
If it weren't for the fact that our environment has been deteriorating
私たちの環境が悪化しているという事実がなければ
We don't necessarily have to develop experiential stuff either.
必ずしも体験的なものを開発する必要もない。
But now I think the most important thing is that the population growth rate is too fast
しかし今、最も重要なことは人口増加率が速すぎるということだと思います
Then pesticide use has a lot
それから農薬もたくさん使われています
The cost for farmers to follow the crowd has been rising
農家が群衆に従うためのコストが上昇している
So there are many kinds of problems
だから色々な問題があるんだよ
Let's not face problems like this
このような問題に直面しないようにしましょう
I think if you can not
それができないならと思う
we better not do
やらないほうがいい
yes
はい
well the time has come
さて、その時が来た
we thank the hospital today
今日は病院に感謝します
thank you
ありがとう